[Thunder Rolling]
[翻滚的雷声]
Voice, Whispering: Antwone. He's here.
安东尼. 他在那.
Woman: That's Antwone.
那就是安东尼.
Woman In White: Antwone?
安东尼?
[Bell Rings, Gunshot]
[铃声, 枪响]
Ohh!
啊!
[Fall Call Whistle Blows]
[口哨声]
Man On PA: First call, first call to colors.
首先集合, 集合升旗.
[Woman On Intercom Speaking Indistinctly]
[广播里妇女说话的朦胧声]
Damn. Berkley!
该死的. 伯克利!
What?
什么啊?
You've been in there 1 0 minutes, man.
你在里面已经10分钟了, 家伙.
Shut up.
闭嘴.
Yeah, okay. You know...
是啊, 行啊. 你知道...
one day, Chief's gonna come in here...
总有一天, 头会来者这儿...
and catch you taking them Hollywood showers.
逮住你正在洗好莱坞淋浴的.
I should snitch on you. Come on, move, man.
我应该揭发你. 快点, 走开, 家伙.
Get out of myway, snitch.
别挡我的道, 告密者.
Oh, come on. Yeah, yeah. Ruff!.
哦, 快点. 是, 是. 出王牌啊!.
Ha ha ha! I gotyou, man.
哈哈哈! 我赢你了, 家伙.
Sailors: Ooh!
嚯!
Arf!.
汪!.
You better quit playing, man.
你最好退出, 家伙.
[Man On Intercom Speaking Indistinctly]
[广播里男人说话的朦胧声]
What's cracking, Fisher?
什么裂缝了, 菲舍尔?
Your head, ifyou don't get away from me.
你的头, 如果你不远离我的话.
Heh. What is that on your face?
嘿. 什么东西在你脸上啊?
Keep the fuck out my face, huh?
该死的不要在我的面前出现, 哼?
Say something!
说话呀!
Say something, huh? You're always talking!
说话呀,哈? 你总是在说话啊!
I'm cool, man, I'm cool.
我很冷静, 家伙, 我很冷静.
I'm cool. I'm cool, man.
我很冷静. 我很冷静, 家伙.
Captain: Petty Officer Fisher, you've been accused...
菲舍尔军士, 你被控告...
ofviolating Article 1 28--
违反了第128条条款...
Assault on a superior non-commissioned officer.
攻击上级军士.
How doyou plead?
你怎样辩护?
Guilty, sir.
有罪的, 长官.
Well, in your statement, you sayyour attack...
啊, 在你的陈述中, 你说你的攻击事件...
on Petty Officer Berkley was provoked by a...
是由于伯克利军士的种族歧视而引起的.
a racial slur. Is that correct?
那样说正确吗?
Yes, sir.
是的, 长官.
Petty Officer Berkley, did you make...
伯克利军士, 你对菲舍尔军士有过任何...
any racial remarks to Petty Officer Fisher?
关于种族的评论吗?
No, sir.
没有, 长官.
Punk, you--
流氓, 你...
Stand at attention!
立正!
Stand at attention.
立正.
This is the United States Navy, son.
这是美利坚合众国的海军, 孩子.
I find you guilty.
我裁决你的罪行.
They'll be a forfeiture of $200 for 2 months.
是罚款两个月，每月200美金.
You'll be restricted to the boundaries ofthe ship...
你在船上有四十五天的禁闭...
for 45 days, and you'll perform 45 days extra duty.
还有你要履行四十五天的额外义务.
I'm reducing you from ship's serviceman...
我把你从舰艇的维护人员...
petty officer third class...
三等兵军士...
to ship's serviceman seaman.
降到舰艇的维护人员水兵.
And I'm recommending thatyou be evaluated...
还有我劝告你...
at the psychiatric clinic...
去精神病门诊部做个评估...
before our next underway period. You're dismissed.
最好是在我们的航行之前. 你被降职了.
So, what happened?
那, 发生什么了?
How'd it go?
怎样了?
Same old, same old. I got busted...
和以前一样, 一样. 我被降职了...
but now I gotta go to the psych clinic.
但是现在我必须得去看精神科医生.
You gotta go to the nut house?
你打算去疯人院?
Farmer, shut up, man.
农民, 闭嘴, 家伙.
Give it up to the shrink? Damn.
对精神科医生绝望了? 该死.
Seeyou next week.
下周见.
Seaman Fisher.
水兵菲舍尔.
Right this way.
这边走.
I understand it's not your first time here.
我获悉这不是你第一次到这儿吧.
You saw Dr. Williams?
你过去看威廉斯医生吗?
Nah, he saw me.
不, 他看我.
Heh.
呵.
That's yourwife?
那是你妻子吗?
Yes.
是的.
Have a seat.
请坐吧.
I understand you like to fight.
我得知你喜欢打架.
It's the onlyway some people learn.
对于有些人来说只有这种办法才能学.
Hmm. Butyou pay the price for teaching them.
唔. 但是你教他们你也付出了代价.
You want to talk about it?
你想谈论这个吗?
About what?
关于什么?
Whatever's bothering you.
困扰你的，无论是些什么.
Why does something gotta be bothering me?
为什么有东西要困扰我?
What, because I jumped on a white boy?
什么, 由于我跳上了一个白人的身上吗?
Something must be wrong with me?
我要有一点错吗?
"Send him to the psychiatrist.
"把他送去看精神病医生.
Nigger try to kill his master."
黑鬼试着去杀死他的主人."
Hmph.
哼.
"He must be crazy."
"他一点是疯了."
You looking for a discharge, Fisher?
你在寻求退伍吗, 菲舍尔?
I ain't looking for nothing.
我什么都不期待.
That's where you're headed.
那就是你所朝的方向.
Ifl want out ofthe navy...
如果我想离开海军...
I'll just leave.
我就会离开.
Unauthorized absence?
未授权就离开?
Yeah, ifthat's what the navy calls it.
是的, 如果海军认为是那样的话.
Hmm. Running away howyou handleyour problems?
嗯. 逃避的话你怎么解决你的麻烦事呢?
I don't have no problems.
我没有麻烦事.
Hmm. Whereyou from, Fisher?
嗯. 你是哪人, 菲舍尔?
Where'd you spend your childhood?
你是在哪度过你的童年时期的?
Cleveland.
克利夫兰.
Parents still live there?
父母还住那儿吗?
I never had any parents.
我从没有父母.
They deceased?
他们已故了?
I never--
我从来...
I never had parents.
我从没有父母.
That would makeyou...
那会使你成为...
a medical miracle, Seaman Fisher.
一次医学界的奇迹的, 水兵菲舍尔.
Whereyou from?
你从哪来的?
I'm from under a rock.
我从岩石下来.
Okay.
好吧.
Okay, all right.
好吧, 行.
I want to seeyou next week.
我希望下星期再见你.
I ain't coming back.
我不会再来.
Why not?
为什么不?
'Cause there's nothing wrong with me.
原因是我没有任何问题.
I agree with you there.
我同意你的看法.
See you next week.
下周见.
See the receptionist on yourway out.
留心一下门口的招待员.
Next Wednesday, 1 400.
下星期三, 十四点.
Whoa!
哇哦!
Walker. Phillip Walker.
沃克. 菲利普-沃克.
That was the name of the last guywho stalked me.
那姓还是上次那个男的告诉我的.
Oh, man, I'm busted.
哦, 家伙, 我被降职了.
Yeah, you're busted.
是么, 你被降职了.
What's up? Whereyou been?
怎么了? 你去哪了?
I'm on restriction.
我在关禁闭.
- Again? - Yeah.
又关了? 是的.
How did you get off the ship?
你是怎样离开军舰的?
Um, well, I just came from the medic.
嗯, 哦, 我正好从医生那过来.
Why?
为什么?
Uh, well...
嗯, 是...
I'm working on this high priority paper...
我现在在做这份重要优先的项目报告...
for this commander.
为这个指挥官干的.
Oh. What kind of paper?
哦. 是什么样的报告?
Well, I'm-- I'm not at liberty...
哦, 我... 我没有权限...
to talk about it right now.
现在谈论这个话题.
Oh. Well, I was gonna inviteyou to a party.
哦. 好吧, 我原打算邀请你参加一次聚会的.
Me?
我?
Yeah, you.
是的, 你.
Well, I'm on restriction.
喔, 我在关禁闭.
Yeah, you told me.
是的, 你告诉我了.
Hmm. I gotta...
嗯. 我打算要...
you know, get back to the ship.
你知道, 我要回舰上去了.
They probably looking for me...
他们大概在找我呢...
right about now, so...you know--
差不多就在这个时候, 因此...你知道...
Talk to you.
不能和你谈了.
[Whispering] Damn.
该死.
Seeyou when you're off restriction.
禁闭后再见.
[Telephone Rings]
[电话铃声]
Yes?
是?
Yeah, send him in.
是的, 把他带进来.
Getyour monkey hands off me, man!
把你这猴子的手拿开, 家伙!
I thoughtyou may have forgotten...
我猜想你可能忘了吧...
yourway here last week, so I took the liberty...
你上星期愿意这样做的, 所以我冒昧的...
of sending an escort team foryou.
派了护卫队把你带来.
You may be able to make me come here...
你也许有办法把我弄到这儿...
but you can't make me talk.
但你不能让我讲话.
Thankyou. You're dismissed.
谢谢. 你们出去吧.
You don't want to talk to me?
你不想和我谈吗?
Let me lay this out foryou, son.
让我来为你安排这个吧, 孩子.
This is how many cases I have, okay?
我这里堆了多少的病例, 看到了吗?
I don't have time to waste.
我没有时间给我浪费.
Now, I get 3 sessions only...
现在, 我只有三个治疗时间...
to make an eval...
来完成一份评估...
and a recommendation to your commanding officer.
和一份建议来给你的指挥官.
You know he wants to throw you...
你知道 他想把你...
out ofthe navy, don't you?
扔出海军,不是吗?
Now, you can sit here, and you can not talk...
现在, 你能坐这儿, 如果你愿意的话...
to me ifyou want to...
可以不和我交谈...
but our sessions don't begin...
但是我们的治疗时间没有开始...
until you begin talking to me.
直到你开始和我对话为止.
I got nothing to say.
我无话可说.
Okay.
好吧.
Then we'll sit until you do.
那就让我们坐着直到你说为止.
I got a whole lot of work to catch up on.
我有这么一大堆的工作来弥补时间.
We can sit here every day...
我们每天都可以坐在这儿...
until the day I retire. Doesn't matter to me.
直到我退休为止. 对我来说没有关系.
It doesn't matter to me, either.
对我也没有关系.
- All righty. - What about the brig?
对的. 那禁闭呢?
What about it?
怎么了?
Send me to the brig.
把我送去关禁闭.
There's the brig right there.
那儿就有禁闭.
Lockyourself up.
监禁你自己.
What doyou know? Time's up.
你知道吗? 时间到了.
Seeyou next week, 1 400.
下周见, 下午两点.
Want some chips?
想要点薯片吗?
Hmph.
不.
[Clears Throat]
[清了一下嗓子]
[Coughing]
[咳嗽]
What?
什么?
I didn't say anything.
我什么也没说.
I thought you said something.
我原以为你说了什么.
Ahem. I was just clearing my throat.
咳嗽. 我只是清了一下我的嗓子.
Okay.
好吧.
[Clears Throat]
[清嗓子]
Maybeyou're coming down with something.
也许你该下去喝点什么.
Ahem. I'm all right.
咳嗽. 我很好.
[Wheezes]
[喘息]
It's just sort of...
只是有几分...
Just what?
只是什么?
Just...
只是...
It's just a waste oftime sitting here...
坐在这只是浪费时间...
week afterweek...
一周又一周...
wasting time.
浪费时间.
I don't want you...
我不想你...
to waste your time, Antwone.
浪费你的时间, 安东尼.
So, whatyou want me to say?
那, 你想让我说什么?
It's not what I wantyou to say.
不是我想要你说什么.
It's whatyou want to tell me.
而是你有什么想告诉我.
Maybeyou can start by asking me a question.
也许你可以先问个我问题.
I don't know. Get things going.
我不知道. 怎样开始.
I can do that.
我可以啊.
You said you come from under a rock.
你说你是从岩石下来的.
What did you mean by that?
你说的那句是什么意思?
I don't know, I...
我不知道, 我...
It was the first thing to come to my mind.
这只是我脑子里首先想到的事.
[Sighs]
[叹息]
What doyou think it means?
你认为什么意思呢?
Well, it could mean...
噢, 它能解释为...
that, uh...
嗯...
thatyou feel under pressure...
你感到有向下的压迫...
uh, you feel a weight...
嗯, 你感到有一种力量...
pressing down on you.
向下压着你.
That you're in the dark, thatyou're alone.
你处在黑暗中, 你很孤独寂寞.
You said you had no parents.
你说你没有父母.
I had parents.
我有父母.
Okay.
好吧.
Ahem. Only 3 sessions, right?
咳嗽. 只有三个疗程, 对吗?
Only 3.
只有三个.
My father's name was Edward.
我父亲叫爱德华.
Soyou knew him?
那你知道他喽?
No.
不.
I didn't even know his last name.
我甚至连他的姓都不知道.
You know where he is?
你知道他在哪吗?
Yeah, I know where he is.
是的, 我知道他在哪.
Joey--
野兽...
He went to his ex-girlfriend's house.
他去他前任女友的住宅.
They got into an argument.
他们有了争论.
She killed my father.
她杀了我父亲.
Where was your mother when this happened?
发生这事的时候你妈在哪儿?
Behind bars.
被关在监牢里了.
I see.
我明白了.
I was born in prison...
我是在监狱出生的...
2 months after my fatherwas murdered.
在我父亲被谋杀的两个月之后.
Whywas she confined, your mother?
她为什么会被关呢, 你的母亲?
I don't know.
我不知道.
All I know is what I told you.
我把我知道的都告诉你了.
Soyou were turned over to the state?
所以你被移交给政府了?
Yeah. The state placed me in this orphanage.
是的. 政府把我安置在这所孤儿院.
It was supposed to be until...
一直幻想...
my mother got out to claim me, but--
我母亲会逃出来认领我, 但是...
She got out, but she never claimed me.
她逃出来了, 但从来也没有来认领我.
Hmm. How long wereyou there?
嗯. 你在那呆了多久?
2 years.
两年.
How does that make you feel, Antwone?
那个事件使你感到怎样了, 安东尼?
I don't know.
我不知道.
Come on, you must have some feelings about it.
快点, 你一定有些感觉的.
You know, you-- What did it feel like?
你知道, 你... 那感觉上像什么?
Rainy days.
下雨天.
Rainy days? Okay.
下雨天? 好吧.
Why is that?
为什么是那个?
You know, in Cleveland...
你知道, 在克利夫兰...
it rains. Not all the time...
下雨. 不是在所有的时间...
but, uh, to a kid...
但是, 嗯, 对于一个孩子...
who wants to go out and play...
他想外出玩耍...
it seems like it rains every day.
天似乎每天都在下雨.
But, uh...
但是, 嗯...
kids expect it to rain sometimes...
孩子希望有些时候下雨...
but...for one kid...
但...对于一个孩子...
it rained too much.
下得太多了.
Hmm.
嗯.
Okay.
好吧.
You want me to come back next week?
你希望我下周还要来吗?
Yes, I do.
是的.
You ever try to find her, your mother?
你曾经试过找她吗, 你的母亲?
No, sir.
没有, 长官.
Okay. Next week.
好吧. 下个星期.
Busy day?
繁忙的一天吗?
Uh, no more than usual.
啊, 和平时差不多.
Hmm.
嗯.
The tomatoes are from our garden.
西红柿是我们家院子里的.
Yeah?
是吗?
Mmm. They're so much better than lastyear.
是的. 他们比去年好很多.
Heh heh.
呵呵.
I mean, I'm no green thumb or anything...
我的意思是说, 我没有特殊的园艺技能 和其他的什么...
but...heh heh.
但是...呵呵.
Who knows? Maybe I'm learning.
谁知道呢? 也许我在学.
These tomatoes really are good.
这些西红柿真的很不错.
Reverend Tate: & I don't know psychology &
∮ 我不了解心理学 ∮
& I don't know astrology &
∮ 我不了解占星术 ∮
& I don't know zoology, ha &
∮ 我不了解动物学, 哈 ∮
& But I know this, ahh &
∮ 但我知道这个, 啊 ∮
&Jesus &
∮ 耶稣 ∮
&Jesus, ha &
∮耶稣, 啊 ∮
Antwone, Voice-over: When I was 2...
当我是二岁的时候...
I was placed in the Tate foster home.
我被安置在塔特的抚养孤儿的家庭里.
Reverend Tate, he was a fire-breathing preacher.
塔特牧师, 他是个烈火中喘息的传教士.
He had his own storefront church.
他有他自己的教堂.
There was only a few members.
只有少数的成员.
There was Ms. Tate, cousin Nadine...
那些是塔特夫人, 表妹纳丁...
my foster brothers Keith--
我的干哥基思...
Keith was halfwhite--
基思有一半是白人血统...
Dwight, and me.
德怀特, 和我.
& Good God, yeah &
∮ 仁慈的上帝, 啊 ∮
It was church 3 times on Sunday...
星期日有三次礼拜...
Bible study on Tuesday...
星期二学圣经...
Y.P.W.W. meetings on Thursday...
星期四有Y.P.W.W.的会议...
choir rehearsal on Friday.
星期五唱诗班排练.
We found out ifwe caught the Holy Ghost...
我们发现如果我们在塔特夫人之前...
in front of Ms. Tate...
感受到圣灵的话...
she'd give us vanilla wafers after church.
她就在礼拜后给我们香草圣饼.
So we'd catch it every Sunday.
所以我们最好每周六都能感到.
& Hallelujah &
∮ 哈里路亚 ∮
& Hallelujah, hallelujah &
∮哈里路亚,哈里路亚 ∮
&Good God &
∮仁慈的上帝∮
&Come on, church &
∮快点, 礼拜吧∮
&Show me &
∮展示给我看啊 ∮
Reverend Tate...
塔特牧师...
he didn't like Dwight at all.
他一点也不喜欢德怀特.
He said he had too much pride.
他说他太骄傲了.
So he tried to beat it out ofhim.
所以他试过把他揍出去.
Sometimes, hewould even tryto beat him to death.
有些时候, 他差不多都要把他打死了.
Did he beatyou?
他揍过你吗?
No, sir. I think he pitied me.
没有, 长官. 我想是他可怜我吧.
And I liked him for it...
我喜欢他对我这样...
but I was ashamed ofhim.
但我也耻于他.
What about Mrs. Tate?
塔特夫人怎么样呢?
What about her?
关于她的什么?
I don't knowwhich one ofyou no-good rotten...
我不知道是你们中的哪个没用的堕落的...
hardheaded niggers putyour dirty hands on mywalls...
顽固的黑鬼 把他那肮脏的手印粘在了我的墙上...
but I bet I'll get the right one.
但是我打赌我会找出这个真正的人的.
I tookyou in...
在被你们那没有用的母亲扔掉你们的时候...
when your no-account mammies threwyou away...
我接纳了你们...
and this is the thanks I get?
这就是我得到的报答吗?
Tsk.
啧啧.
You ungrateful niggers.
你们这些不领情的黑鬼.
[Boys Whimpering]
[男孩的哀求]
[Wailing]
[嚎啕]
Hmph. Now I know I got the right one.
嗯. 现在我想我找到那个真正干的人了.
Antwone, Voice-over: She used to brag about...
安东尼, 她过去常常吹牛...
beating me unconscious.
说把我打到不省人事.
Hmph.
嗯.
She'd threaten to do it again.
她威胁过要再把我打成那样.
But she never did.
但她从未干过.
Why doyou think she never did?
为什么你认为她从未干过?
Uh...maybe she was scared.
嗯...也许她被吓住了.
She found a new way to get me, though.
尽管这样，她还是找到了一个新的办法来对我.
[Young Antwone Panting]
[年轻的安东尼的喘气声]
Soyou like fire, huh?
你喜欢火, 啊?
No, Muh-deah, no, Muh-deah...
不, 不...
I don't like fire.
我不喜欢火.
You...
你...
stay...
离...
away from things that don't belong to you.
那些不属于你的东西远点.
You hear me?
你听到我说的吗?
You hear me?!.
听到我说得了?!
Yes, yes, Muh-deah!
是, 是的!
Yes!
听到我说得了吗?! 是的!
Dumb nigger.
愚蠢的黑鬼.
[Door Creaks Shut]
[门关上了]
Antwone: I tried everything I could...
我试着去做每件能...
to get her to like me...
让她喜欢我的事...
and nothing everworked.
但一件也没成功过.
Wereyou theyoungest ofthe foster children?
你是这些领养的孩子中最小的吗?
No, Dwight was theyoungest.
不, 德怀特是最小的.
I was in the middle, and Keith was the oldest.
我是中间的, 基思是最大的.
Ms. Tate, she used to put us against each other...
塔特夫人, 她过去常常把我们互相对立...
so much, we started hating each other.
因此, 我们开始讨厌对方.
But I think deep down inside...
但我想在内心深处...
we really hated ourselves.
我们真的很恨我们自己.
What doyou mean?
什么意思?
Keith was halfwhite.
基思有一半是半人.
She would try to compare Keith...
她会试着拿基思...
to me and Dwight.
和我、德怀特作比较.
You know, he had the good hair...
你知道, 他有一头好发...
and we had the bad hair.
我们的头发很差.
She used to say how Keith was better than us...
她过去常说基思比我们有多么的好...
because his father was white.
因为他的父亲是白人.
I wished I was Keith.
我希望我是基思.
Mmhh.
嗯.
But not even Keith could escape...
但是不公平的事基思能逃过...
from being called a nigger.
称为一个黑鬼.
She hardly used our names.
她几乎不用我们的名字.
She said the word nigger so often...
她说黑鬼这个词太经常了...
called us niggers so often...
叫我们黑鬼也太经常了...
that we could tell...
我们能说...
who she was talking to by...
只要她在说话...
the way she said the word nigger.
她就会顺便说黑鬼这个词的.
What happened to Dwight and Keith?
德怀特和基思怎么了?
Dwight is in Lucasville State Penitentiary.
德怀特在Lucasville的监狱里.
Keith got taken back by his mother.
基思被他母亲领回家了.
He was raped by one ofher boyfriends.
他被她的的一个男友给抢劫了.
Mmhh.
嗯.
Did what happen to Keith happen toyou?
基思发生的那事对你有什么影响吗?
Hell, no.
该死的, 没有.
Okay.
好的.
Okay. Was Mrs. Tate ever--
好的. 塔特夫人曾经...
Was she ever nice to you?
她曾经对你好过吗?
Yeah, there were times.
是的, 有过几回.
Sometimes she would tell her friends that...
有些时候她会告诉她的朋友...
we were good kids and that she was proud of us.
我们都是好孩子，她很为我们自豪.
Chummy times.
在合得来的时候.
Chummy times?
合得来的时候?
Yeah. I got to where I could tell...
是的. 我已经到这种地步...
what kind of day it was gonna be...
当我醒着的时候 我能通过空气中的味道...
by the scent in the air when I awoke.
辨别出这天是什么样的一天.
How could you tell?
你怎么说呢?
Well, ifl awoke and there was the smell...
哦, 如果我醒着 有一些...
of grits and eggs...
玉米粉和鸡蛋的味道...
orwater steaming off the pavement...
或是在人行道上的水蒸气的味道...
as she hosed it down...
因为她浇湿了...
I had to look out all day.
那我这一整天都得小心.
But...ifl smelled pancakes...
但是...如果我闻到薄饼的味道的话...
everything was okay.
那这天就没事了.
She make pancakes very often?
她经常烙饼吗?
No, sir.
没有, 长官.
I can delay my next appointment...
我能延迟下一个预约...
ifyou want to talk some more.
如果你想多谈会儿的话.
No, sir.
不用了, 长官.
Hey, Slim.
嘿, 斯里.
What?
什么?
You going home next leave?
下次休假你回去吗?
Hell, yeah. I gotta tend to the flock.
该死的, 当然回. 我要看一下羊群.
Hey, when I get leave...
嘿, 当我有休假的时候...
I'm gonna be like a--a vampire...
我打算要像个 像个吸血鬼...
coming to town with his coffin.
带着棺材一起去市集.
Just a place to lay before I get down.
在我到那之前只躺在这个地方.
What's that mean?
什么意思?
Man, shut up. People trying to sleep.
家伙, 闭嘴. 别人还要睡觉呢.
Aw, shutyour grouchy ass up.Jesus!
啊, 闭上你那不满的臭嘴.天哪!
Hey, when you going home, Pork Chop?
嘿, 你什么时候回家啊，猪排?
When your mama quit tripping...
当你妈停止旅行...
and send me my money. Ha ha ha!
还要把我的旅费寄给我的时候，哈哈哈!
What aboutyou, Fish?
你呢, 菲舍尔?
When you going home?
你什么时候回家?
Fish?
菲舍尔?
Fish!
菲舍尔!
Antwone, Voice-over: Last night...
昨晚...
I had a dream aboutJesse.
我做了个关于耶西的梦.
Davenport, Voice-over: Who's Jesse?
谁是耶西?
He was my best friend.
他是我最好的朋友.
When I wasn't at home...
当我不在家...
I was probablywherever Jesse was for 3 reasons.
我大概就会在他哪儿 因为有三个原因.
One was, being his friend...
第一, 只有成为了他的朋友...
he wouldn't beat me up.
他就不会揍我.
Hey,Jesse, look! I got 5!
嘿,耶西, 看! 我抓到了五只!
And the other reasons were-- so he wouldn't beat me up.
另外的原因是.... 所以他不会揍我.
I only got 3.
我抓到了三只.
I liked him a whole lot.
我很喜欢他.
Give meyours.
把你的给我.
We used to drive our friend Kenny crazy.
我们以前常常把我们朋友肯尼弄疯.
Let's get Kenny.
让我们玩一次肯尼.
Kenny hung around me...
肯尼徘徊在我的周围...
for the same reasons I hung around Jesse.
因为相同的原因 我徘徊在耶西的周围.
Hey, Kenny, let me see.
嘿, 肯尼, 让我看看.
Where's Jesse?
耶西在哪?
Ugh!
啊!
Aah! Stop, stop! Get 'em off, get 'em off!.
啊! 停住, 停住! 把那些给我拿出去, 把那些给我拿出去!
Hey, Kenny, what's wrong?
嗨, 肯尼, 怎么了?
don't forget to write!
不要忘记写下来!
Hey, Kenny,
嗨, 肯尼,
Ms. Tate, she hated Jesse.
塔特夫人, 她讨厌耶西.
She hated seeing us together even more.
她讨厌看到我们在一起.
But foryears, she couldn't keep us apart.
但是几年下来, 她也不能把我们分开.
I was so happy when she kicked me out.
我非常的高兴 当她把我赶出去的时候.
Mrs. Tate: Twonny.
东尼.
That hoodlum niggerJesse call up here askin' foryou.
那个流氓黑鬼耶西打电话过来找你呢.
Said something abouty'all going to the picture show.
说了一些关于你们要去看电影的事.
Now, that's the devil's work...
现在, 那是恶棍的干的事...
and who told you you could go...
总之是谁告诉你能去...
to the picture show, anyhow?
去看电影的啊?
I mean, whereyou get the money, nigger?
我的意思是说, 你的钱是从哪来的，黑鬼?
Did you steal it?
你偷的吗?
I already told you. I've been raking lawns.
我已经告诉过你了. 我去帮人除草地了.
Well, you woulda stole it.
啊, 你大概偷的吧.
Give me the money.
把钱给我.
I said gimme the money.
我说把钱给我.
You don't know what to do with no money nohow.
你绝不知道没有钱该干些什么.
That's why I never letyou have none.
就是那个原因 我才一直都给你钱.
Whyyou always got to make things...
你为什么总是把事情...
difficult for me?
对我弄得这么艰难?
Difficult?
艰难?
Difficult.
艰难.
Whereyou learnin' such fancywords at?
你在哪里学的这个奇怪的词啊?
Fancy? Ain't no fancyword.
奇怪? 这不是奇怪的词.
Don't sassy me, boy.
不要对我无理, 孩子.
No one's sassing you.
没有人对你无理.
Don't sassy me!
不要对我无理!
Ain't no one sassing you!
没有人对你无理啊!
Don'tyou--
你不要...
I ain't gonna letyou beat me no more!
我不会再让你打我了!
No more!
不会了!
Lord Jesus.
啊，天哪.
I wantyou out of my house.
我要你滚出我的房子.
Hmm?
嗯?
And whoyou think gonna takeyou in, huh?
你认为谁会接纳你啊, 哼?
Retarded nigger, don't nobodywantyou.
呆滞的黑鬼, 没人要你.
Your damn mammy didn't even wantyou.
连你那该死的妈也都不要你.
Mrs. Tate: Gimme my shoe. Hmpf!.
把我的鞋给我. 哼!.
Davenport: Must've felt pretty good...
一定感到很不错吧...
when you took that shoe from her.
当你把鞋从她那儿拿来的时候.
Yeah, I felt like I was gonna go...
是的, 我感觉上就像我要...
right upside her head...
到她头顶上去了...
but I just chilled.
但是我僵住了.
Why'd you chill?
你为什么僵住了?
I don't know.
我不知道.
Well, I'm glad you did.
好吧, 我很高兴你这样干了.
How'd you feel?
感觉怎样?
I felt like I won a prize...
感觉上就像我得了奖赏一样...
but it scared me.
但是我被吓住了.
Why?
为什么?
It was the first time I ever felt...
这是第一次我感到...
more powerful than her.
比她更强大.
It was like a surprise.
就像一个惊喜.
Whatever happened to Jesse?
耶西到底发生什么了呢?
We lost touch. You know how it is.
我们失去联系了. 你知道事情是怎样了吧.
Davenport: Yeah.
是的.
It might be helpful to understand the mentality...
可能对于了解塔特夫妇这样的人...
of people like the Tates.
的心理状况有点用处吧.
Here.
拿着.
It's called The Slave Community.
这本书叫 奴隶社会.
Why I gotta understand somebody beatin' on me?
我为什么要理解那些揍我的人呢?
What you went through...
你所经受的...
was in part the result ofthe treatment...
只是你得到的待遇的一部分...
that slaves received from their masters...
就像奴隶从主人中得到的一样...
and then passed on to their own children...
然后传递到他们自己的子女中...
generation to generation to generation...
一代又一代，一代又一代...
right on down to the Tates.
然后传到了塔特的一家.
Sir, that sounds like an excuse.
长官, 那听上去是种借口.
I mean, I was a kid.
我的意思是, 我那时还是孩子.
I understand.
我明白.
You sound likeyou takin' up for 'em.
你听上去好像在偏袒他们.
I'm not saying what they did was right.
我没有说他们做得对.
What they did was wrong.
他们做得不对.
We all have choices. They made the wrong choices.
我们都有选择. 他们选错了.
But this is not about them. This is aboutyou.
但这个选择不关他们. 而是关于你.
You were sent to me...
你被送到我这儿...
becauseyou have an anger problem.
是因为你有愤怒的毛病.
Well, you got the right to be angry.
好吧, 你有权力生气.
Butyou also have to learn to channel that anger...
但是你也必须学着去引导那怒火...
to use it constructively.
用在有建设性的方面.
Instead of gettin' into fights...
代替打架...
go to the gym.
去健身房.
Hit the bag, lift the weights.
打沙袋, 举重.
You have to use that energy to betteryourself.
你必须把能量放在对你有益的地方.
You sayyou're taking Japanese classes, right?
你说你在上日语课, 是吗?
Yeah.
是的.
Okay, you're already on the right track.
好吧, 你已经在正确的道上了.
Can we talk about this next week?
我们下周能谈论这个吗?
3 sessions, son. Unfortunately...
三个治疗期, 孩子. 不幸的是...
that's all I'm given to make a recommendation...
我被指定要写份建议...
and I'm gonna recommend...
我打算建议...
thatyou be given a second chance.
给你第二次机会.
That is whatyou want, isn't it?
那是你想要的,不是吗?
To stay in the navy?
呆在海军里?
Yes, sir.
是的, 长官.
Okay. Okay, stay out oftrouble.
好吧. 行, 远离麻烦.
Cheryl: Antwone!
安东尼!
What's up? How you doing?
干吗啊? 你怎样?
I'm cool.
我极好.
Oh. You don't seem cool.
哦. 你似乎不是很好.
I'm all right.
我很好.
What areyou doin' in there?
你在这儿干吗?
You still workin' on that paper?
你仍然在做那份报告吗?
No, I'm finished.
不, 我完成了.
I justwent through there for a short cut.
我为了走捷径而经过那里.
Oh. Whereyou goin'?
哦. 你现在去哪?
Nowhere.
不去什么地方.
I--I gotta go.
我必须走了.
Cheryl, I'll talk toyou later.
我会过会儿和你谈的.
[Laughing Together]
[一起发出的笑声]
Whyyou always talkin' about somebody's momma?
你为什么总是谈论别人的母亲?
Man, we ain't talkin' about somebody's momma.
家伙, 我们不想谈别人的.
We talkin' aboutyour momma!
我们谈你的母亲!
Hey, Fish!
嘿, 菲舍尔!
Yeah, I bet you won't be fightin'
是啊, 我打赌你不会再打架了
no more honkies on this boat.
这艘船上没有白人了.
Man, this ain't no boat.
家伙, 这不是船.
Dis a ship.
这是航母.
"Dis a ship!"
"这是航母!"
Country-ass Negro, who letyou in the navy?
乡下的傻的黑人, 谁让你呆在海军里的?
Fish!
菲舍尔!
What's that book you readin'?
你在看那本什么书啊?
Let me see the cover.
让我看一下封面.
The Slave Community..
奴隶社会..
Whatcha readin' that shit for?
读这个狗屁的干嘛?
Because I want to.
因为我想读.
This ain't no slave ship.
这艘不是奴隶舰.
And these ain't no slavery days.
而且不再是奴隶制度的时期了.
I can't tell.
我不能说.
You the only buck-dancin' Uncle Tom on the ship.
你只会跳舞的黑人 舰艇上的汤姆大叔.
You a part-time brother.
你是个兼职的兄弟.
Yo, Grayson, man, what--
哟, 格雷森, 家伙, 什么...
Whyyou always talkin' shit, man?
你为什么总是说狗屁啊, 家伙?
What I do ain't got nothing to do with you.
我不是没有东西来消遣你.
You better get out of my face, bro.
你最好离我得脸远点, 兄弟.
Eitheryou tryin' to hang out with the brothers...
不管是你要去和那些兄弟们鬼混...
oryou tryin' to hang with the white boys, man.
还是和白人鬼混, 家伙.
You better sit your ass back--
你最好让你的臭嘴休息一下...
You better make upyour mind. Whatyou gonna do?
你最好理一下你的思绪. 你要做什么?
Whatcha gonna do? Come on!
你究竟要做什么? 来啊!
Stop it!
住手!
Let me go! Getyour hands--
让我走! 松手...
[Laughing]
[大笑]
Thankyou, sir.
谢谢，长官.
Who's next?
谁是下一个?
So, um, Dr. Davenport...
那么, 啊, 达文波特医生...
you sent him to the gym?
你把他送去健身房了吗?
Hit the punchin' bags?
打沙袋?
Ain't that what you prescribin'?
那不是你开的药方吗?
So, why areyou here?
那么, 你在这干嘛?
You feelin' under pressure?
你感到有压迫吗?
You feel like, uh, a rock is on top ofyou?
你感到, 嗯, 有块岩石在你头顶吗?
Come on now. Speak the hell up.
快点啊. 该死的快说啊.
You better make it snappy.
你最好爽快点.
You only got 3 sessions comin'!
你接下来只有三个疗程噢!
What arey'all lookin' at?
你们都在看什么?
Whatyou lookin' at?!.
你在看什么?!
You feelin' sick?
你感到不舒服吗?
You need a healin'?
你需要一次治疗吗?
Doyou need a healin', huh? Doyou need a healin'?!.
你需要一次治疗吗, 啊? 你需要一次治疗吗?!.
Some ofy'all sick-ass sailors...
你们中的一些病海员...
need to come back afterworking hours!
都需要在下班后来复原!
See, that's when the good Dr. Davenport...
看, 就在那时候 好医生达文波特...
he'll be layin' his hands on you!
他会把手搭在你的身上!
Or he may have a book in there...
或是那里他会有一本书...
that may have the answers to all your problems...
也许那样就会有解决你全部的难题...
and all your questions! Ain't that right?!.
还能回答你全部的问题! 那不是正确的吗?!
Ain't that right?
那不是正确的吗?
Would you like to step into my office?
你想进我的办公室吗?
[Door Slams]
[关门声]
Areyou finished?
你说完了吗?
I thought I was just gettin' started.
我认为我只是刚开始呢.
Let me tell you something, son.
让我告诉你一些事,孩子.
It may have slipped your mind...
也许你的情绪失去控制了...
butyou are addressing a superior officer.
但是你在演说一位高级官员.
You understand me?
你了解我吗?
Doyou understand me?!.
你了解我吗?!.
Yes, sir. I slipped up.
是的, 长官. 我疏忽了.
You better believe you did.
你就相信吧 你这样干了.
No, sir, I mean I slipped up...
没有, 长官, 我的意思是说我疏忽了...
when I talked toyou.
当我说你的时候.
What?
什么?
3 sessions, right?
三个疗程, 对吧?
That's correct.
那是对的.
Can't be floutin' regulations.
不能违反规章制度.
Well, what do I do, Commander?
好吧, 我要干什么,指挥官?
'Cause I don't know what to do.
因为我不知道要去做什么.
I don't know
我不知道要去做什么.
Tired?
累了吗?
[Chuckles]
[轻笑]
How was your day?
你今天怎样?
Long.
很漫长.
Not complaining, though.
可是，没什么抱怨.
Well, don't wait up.
好吧, 不要等着去睡吧.
I got a lot ofwork to do.
我有很多工作要做.
I know.
我知道了.
- Good night.
晚安.
Well, it's nice to finally be off...
哦, 终于有机会脱离禁闭了...
restriction for a change.
这不是很好么.
Yeah, I'm gonna be squared away from now on.
是的, 我从现在开始就打算要整理了.
Hey!
嗨!
Y'all need somethin' from the exchange?
你需要从商店买点东西吗?
Man, what's up with you and the exchange?
家伙, 你和商店到底发生什么了?
You spend more time there than you do on restriction.
你在那儿花的时间比你关禁闭的时间还多.
I'm just tryin' to be a good shipmate, man.
我只是试着去做一名好船员, 家伙.
I'm only kiddin' with you.
我只是在和你开玩笑.
But bring me back some Skittles.
但帮我带一些绮果果汁脆糖(Skittles).
And a Snickers.
和一个士力架巧克力.
And some pork skins.
和一些猪皮.
And a sandwich. Thankyou.
还有一个三明治. 谢谢.
What areyou doin' here, sir?
你在这儿干什么啊, 长官?
I was in the area and sawyour ship.
我刚才在海边 看到了你这艘航母.
Soyou just saw this big ol' ship...
因此你才见到这这艘旧的...
moored alongside the pier?
停泊在这码头好久了的航母吗?
I want to seeyou back in my office...
我想要在我办公室再见到你...
next Wednesday, after knockoff.
在下星期三, 下班以后.
That is, ifyou want to continue.
就是这事, 如果你想继续的话.
I think I need to check my calender first...
我想我得先检查一下我的日历...
sir.
长官.
Okay.
好的.
Well, you let me know, okay?
行, 让我知道到底怎样, 行吗?
Yes, sir.
好的, 长官.
Hey, Cheryl.
嘿, 谢丽尔 .
- Hey.
嘿.
What's going on?
在做什么啊?
Nothing.
什么都不做.
You just gettin' offwork?
你刚下班吗?
Yeah.
是的.
Oh.
哦.
You, uh-- You mad?
你, 嗯... 你生气了?
Whywould I be mad?
我为什么要生气呢?
I'm sorry.
对不起.
That's cool. [Chuckles]
那很好. [轻的笑声]
So, you finally off restriction?
看来, 你终于不管禁闭了?
Yeah. [Chuckles]
是的. [轻的笑声]
Soyou can hang out now?
所以你能停留一会儿喽?
Yeah.
是的.
So what about now? I'm off.
现在呢? 我现在没事.
Nah, I gotta-- I gotta meet somebody.
不行啊, 我必须得... 我必须得见一些人.
Well, I promised I'd meet somebody...
真的, 我许诺的 我一定要去见他的...
in a few minutes, so...you know.
就这一会儿, 那...你就知道了.
What's her name?
她叫什么名字?
[Chuckles] Look, it ain't like that.
[小笑] 看着, 这并不像那样.
It ain't like that.
不是那样子的.
What about tomorrow?
那明天呢?
Um, what about the day after tomorrow?
嗯, 后天怎么样?
Say, Wednesday, after knockoff?
是, 星期三, 下班后?
That'd be better.
那也许更好.
Okay. Um...
行. 嗯...
meet me in the lobby of the female barracks...
在女兵军营的大厅里见面吧...
at 1 700.
下午五点.
Okay. All right.
行. 很好.
I'll meet you at 1 700.
我会在五点来见你的.
All right. Yeah.
行. 好的.
It's a date.
就这日子了.
Antwone: Are we done?
我们做完了吗?
Davenport: Yes, we are.
是的.
Can I askyou a question?
我能问你一个问题吗?
Sure.
当然.
Um... do you think it's--
嗯... 你认为...
Do you think it's possible...
你认为 有可能...
for somebody that had problems all their life...
对于一些人来说 在他们的一生中都有一些问题...
you know, not to stay that way?
你知道, 不该坚持那样?
You know, you think it's possible...
你认为他们...
they can change?
有可能改变吗?
Absolutely. Why do you ask?
绝对行啊. 你为什么这么问?
No reason.
没有原因.
Do you want something to drink?
你要喝点什么吗?
- No, I'm good, sir. - Okay.
不, 我很好, 长官. 那好吧.
Uh, you know, you--
嗯, 你知道, 你...
You know, when you kinda meet somebody...
你知道, 当你要见一些人...
you know, ifyou have problems...
你知道, 如果你有问题...
it wouldn't--
不会...
Who is she? What's her name?
她是谁? 她叫什么?
Cheryl.
谢丽尔.
She works at the exchange.
我在兑换品商店工作.
That's a good thing. Keep it navy.
那是好事. 选择海军啊.
[Chuckles] Right?
[小笑] 对吗?
So?
接下来呢?
Um... so, um...
嗯... 接下来, 嗯...
Haveyou spoken to heryet?
你和她交谈过吗?
Yeah, I spoke to her, but, um...
是的, 我和她说过话, 但是, 嗯...
I get caught up-- tongue-tied.
我被吸引住了... 说话都结巴了.
Everybody's awkward at first.
每个人的第一次都是笨拙的.
Okay.
好的.
No, not like me.
不, 不会像我那样的.
No, everybody is, Antwone. Trust me.
不, 每个人都是这样, 安东尼. 相信我.
Even you?
你也是吗?
Even me. Everybody.
我也是. 每个人都这样.
So...
那...
Well, we're going out tonight.
嗯, 我们今晚要外出.
Good.
很好啊.
We supposed to go out a couple of days ago...
我们原定前几天就要出去的...
but, uh, you know...
但是, 嗯, 你知道...
I just wanted to clear my head.
我只是想 理一下我的思绪.
Take some time.
花一些时间.
You know, talk toyou first.
你知道, 先和你说.
Okay. Yeah.
行啊. 是的.
So, what should I do?
那, 要我该做什么吗?
[Laughs] Well, she's a nice girl?
[大笑] 那, 她是个漂亮姑娘吗?
Yeah, obviously you like her.
是的, 很明显 你喜欢她.
Mm-hmm.
是的.
Okay, I thinkyou should just go outwith her.
那好吧, 我想你应该 和她一起外出.
I mean...
我的意思是说...
I tell you what. You know, sometimes it helps...
我告诉你啊. 你知道, 有些时候有帮助...
just to take the anxiety out ofa future meeting...
只是用角色表演...
to role play.
来去除一些忧虑.
What's that?
那是什么啊?
Like, you playyourself and I'll play Cheryl...
就像, 你扮演你自己 我扮演谢丽尔 ...
and I'll askyou some questions...
我会问你一些问题...
and we'll have a conversation...
然后我们会进行交谈...
and you'll see that you'll have a good time, okay?
你会知道的 你会玩得愉快的, 行吗?
Yeah, you play Cheryl.
好的, 你扮演谢丽尔 .
Okay, now. That's right.
行了, 现在. 对的.
I'm man enough to play Cheryl.
我是男人足以扮演谢丽尔了.
Okay. Uh, you go first.
行. 嗯, 你先说.
Nah.
不.
I'll go first.
我先说.
So...
啊...
howyou doing?
你好么?
Fine.
很好啊.
Good, good.
不错, 不错.
So, where we gonna go?
啊, 我们打算去哪儿啊?
Out.
外面.
See?
看?
Uh...
嗯...
[Antwone Sighs]
[安东尼叹息声]
I'm hungry. You?
我饿了. 你呢?
I could eat.
我因该能吃.
See? That's good. You got it.
看? 回答很好. 你领会了.
You think so? Absolutely.
你这样认为吗? 绝对是.
I don't thinkyou have anything to worry about.
我不认为你需要担心什么.
I'm gonna giveyou my phone number.
我要把我的电话号码给你.
Ifyou have any problems...
如果你有任何难题...
any questions at all, you can call me.
或是任何疑问, 你都能打电话给我.
Any time of day or night.
不管是白天还是晚上都行.
Have fun. Give me a call, okay?
玩得开心点. 给我来电话, 行吗?
We're gonna be fine.
我们会没事的.
Okay. You never know, son.
行. 你从来都不能预料将来, 孩子.
These things, sometimes they can escalate.
这些事, 有些时候他们会逐步升级的.
Escalate into what?
升级到什么啊?
Mywife and I went out. It escalated into marriage.
我和我妻子外出. 我们的感情就上升到婚姻的地步了.
No, we not escalatin' into marriage.
不, 我们不会上升到这步.
All right, well good. You get outta here.
行了, 非常好. 你必须得走了.
And have fun. Hey...
玩得开心点. 嘿...
have fun.
玩得开心.
- Okay? - I will.
行吗? 我会的.
Okay, seeyou later.
行, 待会儿见.
No escalating.
不升华.
Okay.
行.
Here you go.
拿着.
- Thankyou. - You're welcome.
谢谢. 不用谢.
What is this?
这是什么?
Frappuccino.
Frappuccino.
Frappuccino?
Frappuccino?
Yeah. You like it?
是的. 喜欢吗?
For $6.00?
值六美元吗?
What doyou care how much it cost?
花多少你有什么好在意的?
All the money we're makin'.
我们在创造财富.
That's why I joined the navy, you know?
这个就是我加入海军的原因, 知道么?
To see the world, build a fortune.
游览世界, 创造财富.
I don't know what to do...
我不知道我有了钱以后...
with all the money I got.
我会干些什么.
Okay, now tell me...
噢, 现在你告诉我...
whyyou reallyjoined the navy.
你加入海军的真正原因.
For real?
真的原因吗?
Yeah, for real.
是, 真实的.
All right, well...
行, 是...
my father's a navy man, Vietnam vet...
我父亲是个海军, 越战时的医生...
and, uh, his boys were gonna grow up one day...
嗯, 他的男孩们打算长大以后...
and join and serve just like he did.
都加入和服务海军 就像他干得那样.
Only one little problem. He didn't have any boys.
只有个小问题. 他没有男孩.
- Soyou... - Mm-hmm.
所以你就... 是的.
So I, yep. [Chuckles]
所以我就是了... [小笑]
It's worth it, you know?
这很值, 你知道吗?
I mean, even if I hated the navy--
我的意思是说, 即使我讨厌海军...
which I don't--
其实我并没有...
it's worth it just to...
很值得啊... 当我穿上制服的时候
just to see his eyes and the way they shine...
只要看着他的眼睛 和那种发光的眼神...
when I put on that uniform.
就会觉得很值.
[Chuckles]
[小笑]
So you and him are close?
因此你和他很近喽?
Yeah. We're close.
是的. 我们很亲近.
Mm.
嗯.
Can't wait to go home forThanksgiving.
不能再等了，要回家过感恩节.
You going home?
你回家吗?
I'm gonna go home.
我打算回家.
Mm.
嗯.
I'm kinda hungry. How aboutyou?
我有些饿了. 你呢?
I could eat.
我因该能吃.
[Laughs]
[大笑]
What?
什么事啊?
Nah...
没...
Nothing.
没有什么.
What?
什么?
- What? - You sure?
你肯定吗?
- No. - Okay.
不. 好吧.
You shoulda ordered something.
你因该点些什么东西.
I like what I ordered. These are good.
我喜欢我点的. 那些很好.
You know, vegetables are good foryou.
你知道么, 蔬菜对你有好处.
Want to try some?
想要尝一些吗?
Come on.
来啊.
Try it. It's good.
试试看. 很不错.
It's got, uh, white cabbage...
里面有, 嗯, 白色卷心菜...
purple cabbage, yellow cabbage.
紫色卷心菜, 黄色卷心菜.
Nasty cabbage.
恶心的卷心菜.
[Laughing Together]
[一起大笑]
Man!
家伙!
It's not that bad.
没有那么差.
Mm-hmm.
是的.
So...
嗯...
what doyou like to do?
你喜欢做什么?
Orwhat doyou want to do?
或是你想要做什么?
What would you like to do?
你希望做什么?
I like to do?
我希望做什么?
Mm-hmm.
是的.
Um...
嗯...
Iike, um... I want to teach.
就像, 嗯... 我想教课.
Yeah?
是吗?
My mother was a teacher.
我母亲是教师.
- For real? - Mm-hmm.
真的吗? 是的.
Mm. A teacher's, um...
嗯. 一个老师, 嗯...
I think that's a powerful position, you know?
我想那是个有力的位置, 你知道吗?
You get to give to kids and all that.
你着手于给与孩子 诸如这些事.
I thinkyou'll make an excellent teacher.
我认为你会是个极好的老师.
Really? Thankyou.
真的吗? 谢谢.
I think, um...
我觉得, 嗯...
I thinkyou're beautiful.
我觉得你很漂亮.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
What?
什么?
Well, it's just funny.
哦, 只是有点好笑.
I mean, nice, what happens toyour--
我的意思是说, 好看, 当你笑的时候
Toyour mouth when you smile.
你的嘴怎么了.
One side curls up higherthan the other.
一边翘起 所以它高于另一边.
Did you ever know that?
你过去知道吗?
No.
不.
It's cute.
很可爱.
Oh, thankyou.
哦, 谢谢.
You shouldn't hide it, you know?
你不该把它隐藏掉, 你知道吗?
You should smile more often.
你应该更经常的笑笑.
It's good foryou.
对你有好处.
Yeah.
是的.
Oh.
哦.
Here we are.
我们到了.
You had a good time?
你玩得开心吗?
Yeah. I had a great time.
是的. 我玩得很开心.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
[Sighs]
[叹息]
Well... good night.
好吧... 晚安.
Good night.
晚安.
[SpeakingJapanese]
[日语]
What is that?
那是什么?
Japanese.
日语.
That meant, "It gave me great pleasure...
意思是说, "与你共度今晚...
to spend this evening with you."
是我最大的意愿."
Cool. That was beautiful.
很棒. 那很美.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
So, how do they say...
那, 怎样说...
"Maybe we can do this again sometime?"
"也许有些时候我们还能外出吗?"
Uh...
嗯...
I don't know.
我不知道.
Nah.
不.
Let me know.
告诉我.
I will.
我会的.
Good night.
晚安.
Oh, yeah, I kissed her, man!
哦, 棒啊, 我吻了她, 家伙!
Shoot. [Clears Throat]
哼. [清喉咙]
But I ain't-- I ain't gettin'
但是我不会...
into all the intimate details with you.
牵涉到你的所有的隐私的.
For real. That's just how it is.
真的. 也就那样了.
That's my girl, I respect her and...
那是我的女孩, 我尊敬她...
[Laughs]
[大笑]
Mind yours.
照顾好你的. 照顾好你的女孩.
[Chuckling]
[吃吃的笑]
God, that made me look like a pizza.
上帝啊, 照得我 看去上像一块比萨饼.
[Door Closing]
[关门声]
Hey.
嗨.
[Sighs] Hi.
[叹息]
Ohh.
哦.
Whatcha doing?
你在干吗?
Organizing.
组织起来啊.
These pile up.
这些都积压了.
Well...
哦...
you could start off by gettin' rid ofthat one.
你可以从舍去的那张开始.
Make the pile a little smaller.
因该把建筑拍的小点的.
No, you're gonna have to get in line.
不, 你打算把它拍成一直线的.
Yeah? I rememberthat one.
是吗? 我记得那张.
You can get rid ofthat one, too.
你可以把这张也扔了.
[Laughs]
[大笑]
Look it.
看.
Davenport: Huh.
哈.
Ohh...
哦...
a lifetime ago.
好久以前啊.
Not to me.
对我不是.
[Chuckles]
[吃吃的笑]
Let's see this.
看这张.
What?
什么?
How long are we gonna do this?
我们打算这样干多久呢?
Areyou gonna just keep ignoring me?
你只是打算 继续不离我吗?
Come on, baby. Come on, now.
别胡扯了, 老婆. 别胡扯了, 现在.
What areyou talkin' about? I mean...
你在说什么? 我的意思是说...
we're just having a good time.
我们过的很开心.
Why don't we--
我们为什么不...
You're just gonna continue to act...
你只是打算继续你的表演...
Iikeyou don't know what I'm talking about?
演得就像你不知道我在谈论什么一样?
Look, I don't know whatyou're talking about.
看, 我不知道你现在在谈什么.
You don't know--
你不知道...
I'm hungry, you know? I mean, I walk in--
我饿了, 你知道吗? 我的意思是说, 我走进...
[Doorbell Rings]
[门铃声]
Talk to me.
和我说.
Jerome?
杰罗姆?
She kissed me.
她吻了我.
What?
什么?
I didn't even push her.
我一点也没强迫她.
The only thing I did was I walked her to her door...
我只做这件事了 送她回家...
I threw some Japanese on her...
我对她抛出几句日文...
and then she kissed me.
然后她就吻了我.
Listen, Seaman Fisher--
听好, 菲舍尔海员...
Oh, sir, I'm sorry for knockin' on your door...
哦, 长官, 来敲你的门真的很不好意思...
but I had to. I had to talk toyou.
但是我必须. 我必须告诉你.
Hello.
你好.
I'm sorry for bustin' in on you like this.
很抱歉这样打扰你.
You know, this is highly irregular.
你知道, 这极不礼貌.
Yes, sir, I know. But what am I gonna do?
对, 长官, 我明白. 但是我该怎么做?
I mean, we get underway to Mexico next week...
我想, 下周我们起程去墨西哥...
and I'm startin' to get serious with this girl.
我会认真对待这个女孩.
Okay, okay.
好吧, 好吧.
Well, she'll be here when you get back.
恩，她会在这里等你回来.
How doyou know? Maybe she won't.
你怎么知道? 也许她不会.
Because if she has a fraction ofthe bounce thatyou have...
因为如果她是你奖励的一部分...
she'll be here, I guaranteeyou.
她就会在这里, 我向你保证.
Soyou think I should just chill?
那你认为我改冷一下吗?
That would be a good suggestion.
那是个好建议.
- Chill. Yes. - Okay.
冷静. 是的. 好了.
I won't be doing this again.
我不会再这么做了.
Thankyou very much. Good night.
很感谢. 晚安.
Thankyou, sir.
谢谢, 长官.
You're welcome.
没关系.
Who was that?
那是谁?
A patient of mine.
我的一个病人.
He was, uh... on his first date.
他, 恩... 第一次约会.
He was so excited.
他太激动了.
He couldn't wait to tell me about it.
他等不及要告诉我.
Well, don't cure him.
好了, 别说他了.
Yeah!
嘿!
Show me what you' re worki ng with!
让我看看你干得怎么样!
Show me what you're worki ng with, whoo!
让我看看你干得怎么样, 喔!
Hey!
嘿!
Al I right, man! Fish!
好了，朋友! 菲舍尔!
I don't know about you, but if my math is right...
我不了解你们, 但是如果我没有数错的话...
we a lady short at this table.
这桌少了位女士.
Kansas City: Oh, you ain't know?
哦, 你不知道吗?
My man Fish says he got himself a girlfriend.
我的朋友菲舍尔说 他有女朋友了.
She's in the navy. Right, Fish?
她是个海军. 对吗, 菲舍尔?
Yeah, be writin' to her every minute he can find.
是的, 他不停地写信给她.
Just so romantic.
真浪漫.
Quieres bailar?
您想跳舞吗?（西班牙语）
I don't understand.
我不懂.
Oh, you understand.
哦, 你懂的.
Quieres bailar? Si. Si, bailar.
您想跳舞吗?（西班牙语） 对，对，跳舞.（西班牙语）
I don't know--
我不懂...
She wants to mate.
她要找舞伴.
Do the dance. You understand.
就是跳舞. 你明白的.
Woman: Come, come!
快点, 快点!
Venga, venga.
来吧, 来吧.（西班牙语）
No, I'm fine.
不, 我很好.
Let her oil the old slave down.
别让小姐失望.
What your girlfriend don't know...
你女朋友不知道...
won't hurt you.
不会害你.
Hey, come on, man. Get up, get up, get up.
嘿, 快来, 朋友. 起来了, 起来了, 起来了.
No, I don't want to.
不, 我不想起来.
Grayson: You don't what?
你不想?
You should leave him alone, Grayson.
随他吧, 格雷森.
I'm not botherin' him.
我不想打扰他.
But he didn't answer my question.
但是他没有回答我的问题.
What question?
什么问题?
You don't what?
你不想什么?
How come I never seen you with a girl, huh?
我怎么没有看到你和女孩子一起来过, 哈?
I mean, man says he's got a girlfriend, right?
我是说, 有人说他有女朋友, 对吗?
Well, anybody ever met her?
那么, 有人见过她吗?
Huh?
恩?
Anybody?
有人吗?
Don't worry about it, sweetheart.
别担心,甜心.
You see, he's a cherry boy.
你看, 他是个处男.
Never been to the sugar shack.
没有进过蜜穴.
Too scared to go.
太恐惧了而进不去.
Fuckyou, Grayson.
操你妈的, 格雷森.
Huh? What did you say?
恩? 你说什么?
You heard me.
你听见我说的了.
Fuck me?
干我?
With all these women in here?
和这里所有的女人?
You want me?
你要我?
See what I mean, brothers?
明白我说的了吗, 兄弟?
Hell, I'm worried aboutyou, Fish.
该死的, 我为你担心, 菲舍尔.
I mean, all this action up in here.
我是说, 为这里所有的事.
Whyyou don't want no woman?
为什么你不想要女人?
Yeah. Faggot.
是的. 同性恋.
Here we go again.
我们会再来.
Davenport.
达文波特.
What time does his plane get in?
他大概什么时候到?
Okay. No, no, I understand.
好的. 不, 不, 我明白.
Okay,just let me talk to him first.
好了,就让我先和他谈谈吧.
All right, thankyou.
好的, 谢谢.
I thought we were all done fightin', Antwone.
我想我们都好战, 安东尼.
Let me in.
让我进去.
The X.O. wired the statements ofyour shipmates.
舰长发出了你的朋友的陈述.
Now, doyou wanna start at the beginning?
现在, 你想从头开始吗?
Look, you're gonna have to talk to me, son.
瞧, 你必须和我谈了, 孩子.
You better tell me something...
你最好告诉我...
'cause I'm all you got right now.
因为我现在是你的一切希望所在.
Now, I'm tryin' to work things out...
现在, 我想解决一些事...
with your commanding officer...
和你的指挥官...
butyou gotta give me something.
但是你要告诉我真相.
I don't know what to say.
我不知道说什么好.
So tell me what happened.
那告诉我发生什么了.
Theywere frontin' me.
他们针对我.
What doyou mean, frontin' you?
什么意思, 针对你?
Some ofthe guys were baggin' on me.
有人侮辱我.
I couldn't take it.
我不能接受.
How so?
那怎么样?
I don't know.
我不知道.
Just, uh...
不过, 恩...
just makin'-- makin' jokes.
只是-- 开玩笑.
What kind of jokes?
哪种玩笑?
Jokes about me with--
我和--
With women.
和女人的玩笑.
I wasn't takin' it.
我不能接受.
What kind ofjokes about you bein' with women, Antwone?
你和女人的哪种玩笑, 安东尼?
Jokes like me bein' a virgin.
我是处男的玩笑.
Areyou?
你是吗?
I don't know.
我不知道.
I might be.
我大概是.
Davenport: Okay.
好了.
Why doyou thinkyou haven't been with a woman?
你想过你为什么没有和女人做过?
Think about it, son.
想想吧, 孩子.
Must be a reason. I mean, you're a...
肯定有原因的. 我想说, 你是个...
good-lookin' young man.
英俊的年轻人.
Must've had many opportunities.
肯定有很多机会.
Maybeyou don't like women. Maybeyou like men.
也许你不喜欢女人. 也许你喜欢男人.
I like women.
我喜欢女人.
Maybeyou don't care about sex.
也许你性冷淡.
I care about sex.
我喜欢性.
I think about it all the time.
我会考虑的.
All right. We're right backwhere we started.
好了. 我们回到起点.
How comeyou've never been with a woman?
你怎么从没有和女人做过?
I have.
我有.
Okay.
好.
When?
什么时候?
When I was young. There was--
我小的时候. 是...
There was a kiss.
是一个亲吻.
Okay.
好.
How was it?
那怎么样?
I hated it.
我讨厌那个.
It was t--
那很...
It was terrible.
很恶心.
Why?
为什么?
I threw up.
我吐了.
Because...
因为...
because she put her tongue in my mouth.
因为她把舌头伸进我嘴里.
She--she always did.
她...她老是这样做.
Antwone: That's my mama.
那是我妈妈.
Keith: That ain't your mama!
那不是你妈妈!
You said the other lady was yours!
你说你妈妈是另一个!
I changed!
我换了!
What? You can't change!
什么? 你不能换!
That's my mama!
那是我妈妈!
Mrs. Tate: Nigger?
黑鬼?
Nigger, you hear me callin' you?
黑鬼, 你听见我叫你了吗?
I said nigger.
我说黑鬼.
Comin', Muh-deah!
来了, 穆蒂!
Dwight! Keith!
德怀特! 基思!
Yes, Muh-deah. Here--here I come.
是, 穆蒂. 来了...我来了.
Mrs. Tate: Get your behinds down here.
从这里走开.
And I told y'all not to mess upyour clothes!
我告诉你不要弄乱你的衣服!
- Nadine? - Nadine: Yes?
纳丁? 什么?
We're gonna be downtown...
我们要去市区的...
at the social service office.
社会服务所.
Nadine: All right.
好的.
Twonny? You stay with Nadine.
安东尼? 你就和纳丁待在一起.
Yes, Muh-deah.
是, 穆蒂.
Twonny.
安东尼.
Whatyou lookin' at out there?
你看那边是什么?
Hmm?
恩?
Whatyou lookin' at?
你在看什么?
That's it.
就是这样.
Gimme some sugar.
给我个甜吻.
Now get on downstairs.
现在下楼去.
What did I say?
我说什么了?
Get on downstairs.
下楼.
In that basement and drop 'em.
到地下室 脱衣服.
Nadine: Hurry up.
快点.
Now, unbutton 'em all.
现在，把衣服解开.
Come on.
快.
I said, come on! [Slap]
我说, 快点!
Now, pull 'em down.
现在, 脱下来.
You heard me, pull 'em down.
听我说, 脱下来.
Pull 'em right over my feet.
把衣服脱到脚上.
Now get over here closer.
现在靠近点.
Closer. You don't have to be afraid.
靠近点. 你不用害怕.
Now touch me.
现在摸我.
You know you wanna.
你知道你要什么.
Yeah, that's it. Kiss me.
哦, 就是这样. 吻我.
Come on, now. I said kiss me.
快点, 快. 我说吻我.
Baby, gimme some sugar.
孩子, 给我甜头.
Antwone!
安东尼!
Ooh! I'm gonna tell on you!
哦! 我会告密的!
Jesse: What's up, man? You all right?
怎么了, 朋友? 你还好吧?
Come on in.
快进来.
You all right?
你没事吧?
She did it again.
她又做了.
She hityou, too?
她还打你?
It's okay, Antwone.
好了, 安东尼.
You could stay here.
你可以待在这里.
I'll look afteryou.
我会照顾你的.
Come on. Let's getyou a shirt.
快点. 去穿件衬衣.
She made me--
她让我...
She made me do these things.
她要我做一些事.
And I was only a little boy.
我还是个孩子.
Ifthere was something that I wouldn't do...
如果我不做...
she would beat me.
她会打我.
And Jesse was the only one you ever told?
你就和耶西说过?
Yes, sir.
是的，长官.
She's the onlywoman I ever seen naked.
她是我唯一看到过裸体的女人.
I'm almost 25 years old.
我快25岁了.
I never done it.
我没有做过.
That's embarrassing.
那很尴尬.
I hate it.
我讨厌它.
Yes, can I helpyou with something?
有事吗?
Hello, Ms. Davenport.
你好, 达文波特  .
I'm Seaman Fisher.
我是海员菲舍尔.
Antwone Fisher, ma'am.
安东尼-菲舍尔, 太太.
Well, what can I do foryou?
哦, 我能帮你什么?
I'm here to see the commander.
我来这里见指挥官.
I'm one ofhis patients. He told me to meet him here.
我是他的一个病人. 他要我来这里见他.
Well, he's not homeyet.
哦, 他不在家.
But...
但...
um...
恩...
Well, come on inside. You can wait.
好吧, 进来吧. 你可以等.
Would you like some cider?
来点苹果酒怎么样?
Sure. Thankyou.
当然. 谢谢.
Seems you gettin' all ready forThanksgiving, ma'am.
你准备好感恩节的东西了, 太太.
Berta: Don't call me ma'am.
别叫我太太.
You're gonna make me feel old.
你会让我感觉自己老了.
Call me Berta.
叫我贝塔.
So, areyou going home for the holidays?
那么, 假期你回家吗?
No, but the chief cook on the ship...
不, 长官在船上做菜...
he's plannin' a big meal.
他计划一顿大餐.
So I'll be there forthat.
所以我才会在这里.
That sounds nice.
听起来很棒.
Hereyou go.
给.
Thankyou. Very much.
非常感谢.
Um...
恩...
first thing I saw...
我看见的第一件事...
first time I was in his office...
我第一次去他的办公室...
it was you.
是你.
Yeah. It was your picture.
是的. 是你的照片.
I thoughtyou had a nice face...
我想你很漂亮...
a good face, and... maybe he's all right...
一张漂亮的脸, 也许... 他很好...
ifhe married a woman likeyou.
如果他和你这样的女人结婚的话.
Davenport: You ready to get started?
你准备好了吗?
Yes, sir.
是的，长官.
Nice meetin' you.
很高兴见到你.
It was very nice to meetyou, too.
也很高兴见到你.
Okay.
好了.
I was just tryin' to be nice.
我只是想气氛融洽一点.
Why don'tyou try bein' nice on that ship?
为什么你在船上不和蔼一点?
Hmm?
恩?
Have a seat.
请坐.
I likeyour house.
我喜欢你的房子.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
Tell me about your house.
说说你的房子.
Your house the day you leftyourfamily.
你离开家的时候的房子.
Sir?
长官?
TheTates. When they threwyou out.
塔特一家. 他们遗弃你的时候.
Tell me about that.
告诉我.
Oh. Itwas back to the orphanage.
哦. 它背对孤儿院.
Um...
恩...
they, uh--they told me I needed...
他们,恩--他们告诉我，我需要...
to develop my social skills.
有养活自己的能力.
Nobodywas into adoptin' teenage boys.
没有人想收养十几岁的少年.
Uh...
恩...
they sent me to a reform school...
他们把我送到一家教养学校...
in Pennsylvania.
在宾夕法尼亚州.
That's where I got my excellent skills I have now.
在那里我学会了现在的这些优秀的技术.
[Chuckles] Hmm...
恩...
What then?
然后呢?
Um...I was on my own.
恩...我独立了.
The social worker, she took me to a--
一个社会工作者, 她带我到--
A men's shelter.
庇护所.
She gave me $67...
她给我67美圆...
and, uh...
然后, 恩...
she said good-bye.
她说再见.
How long wereyou at the shelter?
你在庇护所待了多长时间?
Just till the next mornin'.
只待到了第二天早上.
And?
然后呢?
I slept on a few park benches...
我睡在一些公园里的长椅上...
and I came here.
然后我来了这里.
To my house?
到我的房子?
No, sir.
不, 长官.
I joined the navy.
我加入了海军.
That's it.
就这样.
I mean, that's the Antwone Fisher story.
我是说, 这就是安东尼-菲舍尔的故事.
Okay.
好了.
That is it.
就是这样.
You're done for today.
你今天说完了.
Okay, sir.
是的, 长官.
Don't talk to mywife anymore either. You hear me?
别再和我太太说话了. 你听见了吗?
Yes, sir.
是, 长官.
All right.
好.
Davenport: Seaman Fisher.
海员菲舍尔.
Sir?
什么?
Get up here.
过来这里.
What I do?
要我做什么?
Cut the jaw jackin'. Up here right now.
闭嘴. 马上上来.
I don't know what you thinkyou're up to...
我不知道你想怎么样...
butyou better be careful.
你最好小心点.
I didn't do anything.
我什么都没有做.
You didn't do anything?
你什么都没做?
Mywife is inviting you toThanksgiving.
我妻子邀请你参加感恩节.
She thinks you're very charming.
她认为你很迷人.
Doyou have any idea...
你有什么...
where she might've gotten that impression?
她怎么会这样想?
Huh?
恩?
Look at me when I'm talkin' toyou.
我和你说话的时候请看着我.
No, sir.
不, 长官.
Maybe she responds to nice people.
也许她对英俊的男人有好感.
Okay, nice people. Next Thursday.
好了, 英俊的男人. 下周四.
Thanksgiving, my house...
感恩节, 我家...
my family, my dinner table. 1 400.
我的一家人, 我的晚餐餐桌.下午两点.
Don't be late.
别迟到了.
Yes, sir.
遵命, 长官.
Get outta here.
回去吧.
Cheryl: It's nice out here.
这里好美.
How'd you find this place?
你怎么发现这地方的?
It's a lighthouse.
那是灯塔.
I'm a sailor.
我是水手.
It found me. [Laughs]
它发现了我
You knucklehead.
你笨蛋
You come out here a lot?
你常来这里?
Sometimes I come out here to think.
有时候我来这里想问题.
Ortowork out some problems.
或解决问题.
Mmm.
恩.
I know whatyou mean.
我明白你的意思.
Well, um...
那, 恩...
Can I be honest with you?
我可以对你坦白吗?
Yeah.
当然可以.
Rememberwhen I, uh...
记得当我, 恩...
I told you that I was...
我告诉你我是...
I was workin' on that important paper?
我在那家权威报纸工作?
Yeah. [Laughs]
是的
Well, I lied.
恩, 我说谎了.
I know.
我知道.
You know?
你知道?
Yeah.
是的.
You're seein' a psychiatrist, aren'tyou?
你在看精神病医师, 不是吗?
[Laughs] Ohh...
哦...
you knew.
你知道了.
Yeah, I knew.
是的, 我知道了.
It wasn't that hard to figure out.
要知道也不是很难.
Mmm...
恩...
Areyou tryin' to tell me I'm crazy?
你想告诉我，我疯了吗?
No.
不.
So?
那么?
So I'll understand ifyou--
我可以理解 如果你--
Ifyou don't wanna be bothered no more.
如果你不想再被打扰.
You're not the only person...
你不是唯一一个...
that's seen a shrink before.
以前被压抑的人.
Oh, you seen one?
哦, 你见过?
No...
没有...
but I told you my dad's a Vietnam vet.
但是我告诉你我爸爸是越南的医生.
He has.
对，他是.
I guess he made it, huh?
我想他做得很好, 恩?
So, why--why are you seein' a psychiatrist?
那么, 为什么...为什么你去看精神病医师?
My life before the navy was kind of complicated.
加入海军前我的生活很复杂.
I was feelin' ashamed.
我感到羞耻.
Ofwhat?
为什么?
Ofbein' unwanted.
很多余.
And, uh...
然后, 恩...
I didn't have no parents.
我没有父母.
Mmm...
恩...
You know, I was--
你知道, 我是...
I was afraid to even approach you.
我甚至害怕接近你.
Would you believe...
你相信...
that...
那...
I was too shy to approach you?
我很害羞而不敢接近你?
- No. - Yeah. [Laughs]
不是. 是的
Um, until I realized you were stalking me.
恩, 直到我觉得你在接近我.
[Chuckles] I wasn't stalking you.
我没有接近你
Well, ifthere's anything I could do to help...
好吧，如果我帮得上的话...
I'm here.
我随时都在.
You're doin' it already.
你已经这样做了.
What am I doin'?
我做了什么?
Just bein' you.
有你就够了.
HappyThanksgiving.
感恩节快乐.
Um...
恩...
happyThanksgiving. Happy holidays, sir.
节日快乐, 长官.
Happy holidays, ma'am.
节日快乐, 太太.
I know.
我知道.
It's...Berta.
那是...贝塔.
Yeah.
是的.
Come on--come on in.
快--快进来.
Hello.
你好.
I'm Antwone. [Ahem]
我是安东尼.
I, um...
我, 恩...
Yeah, I'm hungry.
恩, 我饿了.
I could eat. [Laughs]
我会吃.
1 400, huh? What tookyou so long?
下午两点, 哈? 怎么这么久?
Oh, I stopped by to get some cider, sir.
哦, 我顺便拿了点苹果酒, 长官.
Okay. Good. Happy holidays.
好. 太好了. 节日快乐.
Thankyou. Come on in.
谢谢. 请进.
Everybody's here waitin' foryou.
所有人都在等你.
We're about to say grace.
我们要做饭前祷告.
All right, everybody. This is Antwone.
好了. 他是安东尼.
Antwone, this is my family.
安东尼, 这是我一大家子.
That's my mother Johnny Mae.
她是我妈妈 珍妮-梅.
That's mywife's brother Uncle Duke.
那是我妻子的兄弟杜克叔叔.
- Howyou doin'? - Hello, sir.
你好吗? 你好, 先生.
This is my dad Howard.
这是我爸爸霍华德.
That's my sister Gwen...
那是我姐姐格温...
and her full-grown daughter.
和她丰满的女儿.
Hi, Antwone.
嗨, 安东尼.
Oh, you wanna come and sit next to her?
哦, 你想坐在她边上吗?
Gwen, Gwen. Uh...
格温, 格温. 恩...
Come on, baby.You come on over here and sit.
来吧, 孩子.你可以过来坐.
Okay.
好的.
Davenport: All right.
好了.
Duke, why don'tyou lead us in prayer?
杜克, 你为什么还不带我们祈祷?
Okay.
好.
Everybodyjoin hands.
大家手拉手.
Let's bow our heads.
低头.
Heavenly Father...
仁慈的上帝...
we come to you on bent knee...
我们向你屈膝...
and body bowed...
弓身...
as humble as we know how.
我们是那么的卑微.
We are grateful for this opportunity...
我们感谢你给我们这样的机会...
to share another Thanksgiving Day...
分享感恩节...
as a family.
作为一个家庭.
We thankyou for our health...
我们感谢你给我们健康...
O Lord, and for our friends...
哦 上帝, 为我们的朋友...
who honor us with their presence.
他们的出席让我们荣耀.
We also pray for peace in the world...
我们也祈祷世界的和平...
and in our lives. Amen.
生活的宁静. 阿门.
All: Amen.
阿门.
All right.
好了.
This looks good. Yeah!
看起来真棒. 对!
Here's a little piece.
来一片.
Thankyou. Mmm.
谢谢. 恩.
Honey, you want some more turkey?
亲爱的, 火鸡要吗?
Oh, no, thankyou, ma'am.
哦, 不, 谢谢, 太太.
Howard: Ohh, don't be actin' all bashful around me.
哦, 在我这里别害羞.
Especially at the dinner table.
特别是在餐桌上.
Dad, leave that boy alone.
爸爸, 别管他了.
Shoot!
妈的!
Huh? I'm okay.
哈? 我很好.
All right, then, let me seeyou dig in.
那就好, 吃吧.
I mean, the food is free.
我是说, 免费的.
Howard...
霍华德...
You know, when I was in the service...
你知道, 我服役的时候...
back in the war--that was before you were born--
战争里回来...那是在你出生前...
Howard!
霍华德!
Anyway, I spent the holidays...
不管怎样, 假期很愉快...
in Europe on guard duty, and I--ohh!
在欧洲值勤, 我--哦!
I sure did miss my mama's holiday cookin'. Whoo-oo!
我当然不能错过太太的节日特餐. 喔喔!
Howard, would you leave the boy alone?
霍华德, 你别管他行吗?
Oh, I ain't botherin' him none,Johnny Mae.
哦, 我不会再打扰他了,珍妮-梅.
No, you leave me alone, huh?
不, 你不管我, 哈?
Baby, he wants to eat!
亲爱的, 他要吃!
Oh, no, look, I'm just talkin' to the boy.
哦, 不, 看, 我只是在和男孩说话.
I'm sure he wants to be home with his family, okay?
我想他想和他的家人在一起, 对吗?
Hey, listen, let me askyou something.
嘿, 听着, 我要问你些事.
Whereyou from?
你是哪里人?
[Ahem] Cleveland.
克利夫兰.
Cleveland. Yeah?
克利夫兰. 是吗?
Yeah.
是的.
Cleveland...
克利夫兰...
I betyou miss your mama's holiday cookin'...
我希望你忘了你妈妈的节日特餐...
don'tyou? Huh?
不会吧? 哈?
Excuse me.
对不起.
Where he goin'?
他去哪里?
Howard: I don't know.
我不知道.
See? That's what happens every holiday season.
看见了吗? 每个节日都会有事发生.
Why doyou want to do that to the boy?
你为什么要那么做?
Y'all ran the boy outta here!
你把那孩子赶跑了!
That's what happens every holiday!
这就是每个节日发生的!
I didn't run the boy out. I was tryin'
我没有赶他走. 我是想...
to talk to the boy.
和他聊天.
You okay?
你没事吧?
Yes, I'm okay.
没事, 我很好.
I just never had a real Thanksgiving...
我从没有有过真正的感恩节...
at the Tates' before.
以前在塔特家.
[Snorts] You didn't have a real one...
你没有过真正的...
over here either, I guess. [Chuckles]
我想这里也是
You have a real nice family.
你有一个很温馨的家.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
I got this foryou...
我得到了...
for having me over today.
今天你带我来.
Oh, you got a gift for me. Is it money?
哦, 你给我礼物. 是钱吗?
No. [Laughs]
不是
Oh, it's a poem.
哦, 是首诗.
I can't see without my glasses.
没有眼镜我看不见.
Why don'tyou read it for me?
你为什么不念给我听?
Um, I'd rather you read it.
恩, 我宁愿你来念.
Please.
拜托.
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?
"Lost and all alone.
"迷惑和独立.
"Abandoned without his own.
"没有自暴自弃.
Who will cry for the little boy?"
谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?"
Both: "He cried himselfto sleep.
他哭泣着入眠.
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?
Who never had for keeps."
谁也没有永远"
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁为愿意那孩子哭泣?
"Who walked the burning sand.
"走过热沙的人.
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?
"The boy inside the man.
"孩子在他心里.
"Who knew well hurt and pain.
"明白他的疾苦.
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?
"Who died and died again.
"一次次的死亡.
"A good boy he tried to be.
"他想成为好孩子.
"Who will cry for the little boy?
"谁愿意为那孩子哭泣?
Who cries inside of me?"
谁在我心里哭泣?"
Who will cry for the little boy, Antwone?
谁愿意为那孩子哭泣, 安东尼?
I will.
我愿意.
I always do.
我一直愿意.
It's beautiful, Antwone.
太美了, 安东尼.
I know. I told you I was good.
我知道. 我告诉你我很棒.
Yes, you are. You are good...
是的. 你很棒...
because you're honest.
因为你诚实正直.
You're more honest than most people...
你比很多人诚实...
even in your anger.
甚至在你生气的时候.
The only thing you're not honest with yourself...
你对自己唯一不诚实的...
about is your need to find your own family.
是对自己家庭的渴望.
Your natural family.
你自己的家.
I don't feel like I need to look for them.
我不觉得我需要找他们.
Mmm. It would answer a lot of questions foryou.
恩. 有很多问题要回答你.
I don't have any questions.
我没有问题.
You're upset with them...
你对他们很心烦...
becauseyou feel they didn't come toyour rescue.
因为你觉得他们不需要你.
Maybe they didn't know.
也许他们不知道.
How could they not have known?
他们怎么不知道?
That's a question you need to ask them.
那是你需要问他们的问题.
"Regard without ill will...
"没有恶意...
despite an offense."
尽管进攻."
That's Webster's definition offorgiveness.
这时韦伯斯特对宽恕的定义
Why do I have to forgive?
为什么我要饶恕?
To freeyourself...
要解放你自己...
so thatyou can get on with your life.
那样你可以继续你的生活.
Why I gotta go look for my family?
为什么我要回去我的家?
I got you, Doc.
我明白了, 医生.
Berta: Ohh...
哦...
I think that he had a good time tonight.
我想他今晚过得很好.
Davenport: Hmm?
恩?
Antwone. I think that, uh...
安东尼. 我这样想, 恩...
he had a good time, don'tyou?
他过得很好, 你不这样想?
Yeah, seemed like it.
是的, 看起来是的.
He did the sweetest thing at the door...
他做了最甜美的事...
when he was saying good-bye.
当他说再见的时候.
He invited me to come to his ceremony.
他邀请我去参加他的典礼.
You know he's graduating from his Japanese class.
你知道他从日语班毕业了.
Yeah, I know.
对，我知道.
Well, he wants me to come.
恩，他想要我去.
To be with you.
和你一起.
What did you tell him?
你对他说了什么?
I told him that I would be honored,Jerome.
我告诉他我很荣幸,杰罗姆.
Okay...
好...
okay.
好的.
Congratulations.
祝贺你.
Petty Officer Fisher. Good job.
菲舍尔士官. 好工作.
Thankyou, Commander.
谢谢, 长官.
I was waiting. Cheryl, right?
我在等待. 谢丽尔 , 是吗?
[Chuckles] Howyou doin', Cheryl?
你好吗, 谢丽尔 ?
It's a pleasure to meetyou.
很高兴看到你.
Heard nothin' but good things aboutyou.
只听到你的好事.
Where's yourwife?
你妻子在哪儿?
She couldn't make it.
她没来.
She sends along her congratulations.
她一路送上祝福.
A small gift foryou.
有个礼物给你.
Okay.
好的.
The Philosophy.and Opinions ofMarcus Garvey..
马库斯-加维的哲学与观点..
Thankyou, sir.
谢谢, 长官.
You're welcome.
别客气.
Is there somewhere we can talk in private?
我们可以私下聊一会儿吗?
Do you mind?
你介意吗?
That's fine. I don't mind.
很好. 我没问题.
Okay. Nice to meetyou.
好的. 很荣幸见到你.
Nice to meetyou, sir.
很荣幸见到你, 长官.
Hello?
嗨?
[Sighs] What's up, Doc?
怎么了, 医生?
How areyou?
你好吗?
I'm good.
我很好.
Yes, you are, Antwone.
哦, 你好, 安东尼.
You're good.
你棒极了.
I hear nothin' but good things...
我只听到了好事...
from your C.O.
从你的长官那里
Hear thatyou're gettin' along verywell...
听说你...
with your shipmates. I'm proud ofyou.
和你的同事相处得很好. 我为你骄傲.
Thankyou, sir.
谢谢, 谢谢.
Haveyou thought anymore about finding yourfamily?
你想过找你的家人吗?
I don't know. Forwhat?
我不知道. 为什么?
Well, I just think that there's really nothing...
恩, 我只是想真的没有什么...
more important than that, Antwone.
比那更重要的, 安东尼.
What areyou tryin' to say, sir?
你想说什么, 长官?
That I'm proud ofyou...
我以你为豪...
that I think you've come a long way.
我想你还有很长的路要走.
Okay.
好.
You said that. What's wrong?
你说了. 怎么了?
There's nothin' wrong.
没有什么.
You understand, this is very difficult for me.
你明白的, 这对我来说很难.
Our sessions have ended.
我们的会谈结束了.
[Exhales] Now, listen.
现在，听着.
Just listen to me, all right?
就听我说, 好吗?
I've taken the liberty of--
我有权--
What doyou mean, they ended?
什么意思, 他们结束了?
They--They ended, son, and it's time foryou...
他们--他们死了, 孩子, 对你来说是时候...
to move on. You can't stall here.
继续前进. 你不能待在这里.
Butyou and me are workin' out my problems.
但我和你都在解决我的问题.
You and me can't work out--
我们不能解决--
You told me that we need...
你告诉我我们需要...
to figure out my problems.
解决我的问题.
- Listen to me-- - Get off me!
听我说-- 绕了我吧!
[Door Opens] Hey, get out!
嘿, 出去!
- Get out! - Nobody ever stays!
出去! 没有人会停下来!
Everybody's always leavin' me!
所有人都抛弃我!
People grow. People move on.
人们长大了. 人们不断前进.
You've grown. It's time foryou to move on.
你已经长大. 你该继续前进.
Hey, my mother left me!
嘿, 我妈妈遗弃了我!
My father! I understand--
我爸爸! 我明白...
Jesse and you!
耶西和你!
Jesse? What doyou mean?
耶西?你什么意思?
We shoulda never gone, that's what.Jesse!
我们没有离开, 就是这样.耶西!
Jesse? Tell me something--
耶西? 告诉我...
Cow bells ringin' in my fuckin' head!
我脑袋里有牛铃响起!
Cow bells? Tell me about the cow bells--
牛铃? 告诉我牛铃的事--
But I keep trustin' people!
但我一直相信人!
Trustin'...
相信...
What happened toJesse, Antwone?
耶西怎么了, 安东尼?
Stay away from me.
离我远一点.
Nobody's takin' anything else away...
没有人会拿走什么...
from me no more.
从我这里.
Jesse: Who is it?
谁?
Jesse: Man, I just asked who was it.
朋友, 我只是问是谁.
Fish! Oh! [Laughs]
菲舍尔! 哦!
Hey, what's up, dog?
嘿, 怎么了, 伙计?
What's up with you, man?
你怎么了, 朋友?
What's goin' on with you, man?
你怎么回事, 朋友?
Hey, man, stop playin'.
嘿, 朋友, 别玩了.
Stop playin'? All right...
别玩? 好...
don't make me kickyour ass now.
别让我踢你屁股.
You knowyou can't fight worth shit.
你知道你会动手.
Man...
嗨...
What's up with you, man?
你怎么了, 朋友?
with you?
你到底怎么了?
Whereyou been at?
你去过什么地方?
Whereyou stayin'? What's up?
你呆在什么地方? 发生什么了?
Huh?
哈?
I'm at the men's shelter.
我在庇护所.
On Prospect.
被希望的.
Whereyou stayin' at, man? For real.
你在什么地方, 伙计? 说真话.
I'm on the street.
我在街上.
Whatyou doin' on the streets, man?
你在街上做什么, 伙计?
I got nowhere else to go, man.
我没有地方可以去了.
You ain't got nowhere to go.
你不会没有地方去的.
You couldn't come to my house?
你不会到我这里来吗?
No, man. Your mom ain't gonna let me stay up in here.
不. 你妈妈不会让我在这里迟睡的.
You trippin', man. She ain't gotta know.
你在流浪, 伙计. 她不会知道.
I mean, she work all day...
我是说, 她整天都工作...
sleep all night. Besides...
整晚睡觉. 而且...
there's so many people stayin' up...
有很多人晚睡...
in this house, [Chuckles]
在这个家里,
She wouldn't even know you're here no way, dog.
她不会知道你在这里的, 伙计.
You can stay here, for real.
你可以待在这里, 真的.
Y'all got something in the refrigerator?
冰箱里有东西吗?
Yeah, we got something...
对，有一些...
You hungry?
你饿了?
- I'm hungry. - You hungry?
我很饿.
- Yeah, man. - "Yeah, man."
是的. "是的."
- Stop playin'. - Come in here.
别玩了. 进来吧.
I mean, you smell like you been...
我想, 你闻起来有...
on the streets, too, man.
在街上的味道.
Dang, slow down, man.
天哪, 慢点.
Ain't nobody gonna takeyour food.
没有人抢你的东西吃.
Hey--Hey, you remember that time...
嘿--嘿, 你记得那次...
Mrs. Tate wouldn't letyou use her lotion?
塔特太太 不让你用她的洗剂吗?
She madeyou oil up with old cooking grease instead.
她要你用老油.
You walking around all day...
你走了一整天...
smelling like a fried chicken dinner.
闻起来像炸鸡肉.
You like, "I sho' is hungry!"
你喜欢, "我当然饿了!"
Man, that was so funny.
那很滑稽.
That had me rolling for real.
那真让我要倒下了.
But not as funny as your mother...
但没有你妈妈滑稽...
chasing you down the street with that brick.
沿着街道拿着那块砖追赶你。
Oh, okay, okay. You remember that?
哦, 好了, 好了. 你记得那些吗?
Yeah, I remember that.
是的, 我记得.
That was funny.
那很滑稽.
Dude, that wasn't funny, man.
家伙, 那不滑稽, 伙计.
I still got the knot in the back of my head.
我的后脑勺还留着疤.
Fish, you know you're my best friend, right?
菲舍尔, 你知道你是我最好的朋友, 对吗?
Whatyou want?
你想说什么?
What, I can't be happy my dude back on the block?
什么,我的花花公子回来了我能不高兴?
Huh? I can't be happy you back here at home, man?
哈? 你回到家里我就不能高兴, 伙计?
I wantyou to do something for me, though.
我要你答应我件事.
What?
什么事?
Just look out for me.
只是看好我.
Somebody afteryou?
有人追你?
Why somebody got to be after me, man?
为什么有人要追我, 伙计?
Huh?
哈?
I just wantyou to look out for me, dude.
我只是要你替我看看, 家伙.
All right.
没有问题.
You my best friend, right?
你是我最好的朋友, 对吗?
Yeah, man. Stop trippin', man.
对, 朋友. 别再流浪了, 伙计.
Man, come on. Let's getyou cleaned up...
伙计, 快点. 收拾一下...
and hit the streets.
出去逛逛.
Yeah, I don't know.
恩, 我不知道.
You know Brenda. I used to like her.
你认识布伦塔. 我曾经喜欢过她.
Psh. The Brenda you used to like, dog...
你喜欢过的布伦塔,伙计...
got about, like, 3 kids now.
现在生了大概3个孩子.
Gettin' all swole. She big for real, dog.
她变胖了. 非常胖, 伙计.
Ain't no little bootie Brenda no more.
布伦塔不再是那个小可爱了.
Hey, how's your mother?
嘿, 你妈妈现在怎么样?
Aw, tsh, man, she got knocked up.
噢, 朋友, 她很疲惫.
For real?
真的吗?
Yeah.
当然.
Jesse: It's bad.
很糟糕.
Go ahead, man. Getyou something.
走吧. 你买些东西.
I gotyou.
我收留了你.
Break it off, old man!
闭嘴, 老男人!
Jess, whatyou doing?
耶西, 你在干吗?
This ain't no riddle.
别瞎猜.
This ain't nothing you got to figure out.
你别多想.
-Jess-- - Hey, hold off, Fish.
耶西... 嘿, 住嘴, 菲舍尔.
Hey, you better break off my loot!
嘿, 你最好把钱拿出来!
- Hey,Jess, man-- - Look out for me, Fish.
嘿,耶西, 我的朋友... 看好我, 菲舍尔.
Antwone: And by the end ofthe next day...
到明天结束的时候...
I was in boot camp.
我会在靴子阵营.
I always felt like Jesse was the lucky one...
我一直认为 耶西很幸运...
and I envied him for it.
我羡慕他.
Well, how could he be the lucky one? He's dead.
恩, 他怎么幸运了? 他死了.
Yeah, well, he left me...
对, 他丢下了我...
and he knew he was the only one I had.
他知道他是我唯一的朋友.
So, you're angry at him...
所以, 你很气他...
becauseyou felt he abandoned you.
因为你觉得他抛弃了你.
Yes.
对.
A little bit.
有一点.
How is he the lucky one?
他怎么幸运了?
'Cause he don't have to fight no more.
因为他不用再参战.
Neither doyou.
你也一样.
So, you think I'll make it?
那, 你认为我会成功?
I think you already have.
我以为你已经成功了.
What doyou think?
你怎么想?
I think, uh...
我以为, 恩...
maybe in another life ortime...
换一种生活或换个时间...
I would have been king.
我会是国王.
When you locate your family...
等你定下来的时候...
I wantyou to contact me.
记得告诉我.
All right? I want to hear all about it.
好吗? 我想知道所有的事.
Yes, sir.
好的, 长官.
I loveyou, son.
我爱你, 孩子.
[Voice Breaking] I loveyou, too.
我也爱你.
Who's this?
是谁?
Guess who.
猜猜看.
Antwone.
安东尼.
No, this is Phillip Walker...
不是, 是菲利普-沃克...
the late-night stalker.
深夜捕猎者.
Aw.
噢.
Ha ha ha ha.
哈哈哈哈.
So...
那么...
I, um, I'm going on leave.
我, 恩, 我正打算离开.
When?
什么时候?
As soon as you put your request in...
你提出你的要求...
and come with me.
和我一起来的时候.
You serious?
你是认真的?
Yes.
当然.
I just came back.
我就回来.
They're not gonna let me leave again this year.
他们今年不会再要我走了.
Can you ask for emergency leave?
你会请求紧急离开吗?
Tell them somebody close toyou...
告诉他们你的一个好友...
is in desperate need.
非常需要你.
Cheryl, I--
谢丽尔 , 我--
I reallywantyou to come with me.
我真的想要你和我一起来.
I got these, uh...
我有, 恩...
2 open tickets.
2张票.
To Cleveland.
去克利夫兰.
You're gonna try and find them.
你要去找他们.
Yeah. I need to find them.
是的. 我必须找到他们.
But not without your help.
但没有你的帮助我做不到.
All right. Let me see what I can do.
没有问题. 看看我能做些什么.
Antwone: First the light-skinned girls.
首先白皮肤的女孩.
They got adopted the quickest.
他们往往最快被收养.
Then the light-skinned boys...
接着是白皮肤男孩...
and then the dark-skinned girls...
然后是黑皮肤女孩...
and then, last but not least...
然后, 最后但不是最少...
the dark-skinned boys.
是黑皮肤男孩.
I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉.
All birth records since 1 980...
所有1980年以后的的出生日期...
have been moved to social services.
都已经在社会收容所了.
Woman: Last contact with your mother?
最后一次和你妈妈联系是什么时候?
I was 2 months old.
我2个月大的时候.
And with father?
和你爸爸呢?
Never.
从没有.
Place ofbirth.
出生地点.
Ohio State Correctional Facility forWomen.
俄亥俄州立女子帮助机构.
I'll be right back.
我马上回来.
I need you to sign for me.
请给我签个字.
Best ofluck, Mr. Fisher.
祝你好运, 菲舍尔先生.
Thankyou.
谢谢.
Antwone: There's nothing in here.
什么都没有查到.
Why don'tyou go see your foster mother?
你为什么不去看看你的养母?
- Who, Mrs. Tate? - Yeah.
谁,塔特夫人? 对.
I'm not--I'm--
我不-我...
I'm not going back.
我不想回去.
Well, why not?
恩, 为什么不?
I mean, she might know something aboutyour family.
我以为, 她可能知道一点你家的事.
No.
不.
I haven't done this before.
我以前从没有这样做过.
Take a ride with me.
我可以载你去.
Ifyou selling shit, just keep on walking.
如果你卖了这东西,就只有一直走了.
Oh, my God. Is thatyou, Antwone?
哦, 天哪. 那是你吗, 安东尼?
Come here, baby.
过来, 宝贝.
Don't touch me.
别碰我.
Yeah, it's me...
哦, 是我啊...
and I'm all grown up.
我已经长大了.
I'd like to speak to Ms. Tate.
我想和塔特夫人谈谈.
Well, you want to come in?
哦, 你要进来吗?
No.
不.
Would you like to get her?
你可以通知她吗?
'Twon's here.
安东尼来了.
Mrs. Tate: Lord have mercy.
可怜的上帝.
Where's the child?
那孩子在哪里?
Oh, nigger! Hug my neck.
哦, 黑鬼! 抱我.
Oh, nigger.
哦, 黑小子.
I-- Don't you know how to come home?
我-难道你不知道回家的路吗?
Whereyou been?
这些年你都去了哪里?
I came for one thing:
我回来只为一件事:
whateveryou can tell me about my real family.
你能告诉我,我亲生父母的事吗.
I don't know nothing aboutyour real peoples.
对于你的亲生父母,我不清楚.
A name, number, anything?
名字, 电话, 其他的什么?
I said I don't know.
我说了我不知道.
Now, come along. Come on.
那, 我们继续. 快点.
I remember everything.
我记得所有的事.
Everything.
所有的事.
You could have helped me...
你本来可以帮助我...
but instead, you beat me to dust, and you--
但, 你反而视我为尘土, 你--
Boy, I don't know whatyou're talking about--
孩子, 我不知道你在说什么--
Yes, you do. I was 6 years old!
不, 你很明白. 那年我6岁!
Now, you just listen--
现在, 你就听我说--
No, you listen to me!
不, 你听我说!
No, I thinkyou done forgotten--
不, 我想你大概已经忘了--
I thinkyou forgotten. I said listen to me.
我想你忘了. 我说你听我说.
This is my time.
现在该我说了.
You understand me?
你明白吗?
It don't matter...
那无关紧要...
whatyou tried to do.
你想做什么.
You couldn't destroy me.
你不能毁了我.
I'm still standing.
我没有倒下.
I'm still strong.
我仍然强壮.
And I always will be.
我一直如此.
Antwone.
安东尼.
Elkins.
厄尔京.
Yourfather's name was Edward Elkins.
你父亲叫爱德华-厄尔京.
You take Shaker Heights and East Cleveland...
你找夏克海茨和东克利夫兰...
and I'm gonna take Akron and Cleveland.
我打算找 阿克伦城和克利夫兰.
Yeah. 1 976.
恩. 1976年.
Hello. Hi, um...
你好. 嗨, 恩...
I'm looking for the family of Edward Elkins.
我在找爱德华-厄尔京的家.
Cheryl: Edward Elkins.
爱德华-厄尔京.
Cheryl: Hello.
你好.
Hi, I'm looking forthe family...
嗨, 我在找...
no--Ed-ward.
没有...爱德华.
E-D-W-A-R-D.
E-D-W-A-R-D.
What? I'm speaking clearly.
什么? 我说得很清楚了.
You can't--
你不能...
Okay.
好了.
Well, thank-- thankyou.
恩, 谢谢... 谢谢.
I'm looking for the family...
我在找...
of an Edward Elkins.
爱德华-厄尔京的家.
You should have said that in the first place.
你在第一个地方已经说过了.
Wha--whyyou...
什么-你为什么...
[Mutters] Forget it, man.
忘了吧, 朋友.
Yeah, well, we're from California.
好吧, 我们从加利福尼亚来.
Yes, it's very nice here.
哦, 那是个好地方.
Okay, well, thankyou foryour help, ma'am.
好了, 好了, 谢谢你的帮助, 太太.
Thankyou. Bye.
谢谢. 再见.
Any luck?
有消息吗?
Whatyou got?
你呢?
Chinese.
中餐.
Hello?
你好?
Antwone: Hello, ma'am.
你好,太太.
Yes?
什么事?
I'm looking forthe family...
我在找...
ofan Edward Elkins.
爱德华-厄尔京一家.
Hmm?
什么?
Wh-who is this calling about Edward?
谁-谁在谈论爱德华?
My name is Antwone Fisher.
我是安东尼-菲舍尔.
I didn't mean to disturbyou.
希望没有打扰你.
I'm just trying to locate myfamily.
我只是想找我的家人.
Honey, Edward Elkins been dead...
亲爱的, 爱德华-厄尔京已经死了...
a long time.
很长时间了.
Yes, ma'am, I know...
是的, 太太, 我知道...
a long time, but he was my father.
很久了, 但他是我父亲.
Wait, wait, wait. Who is this...
等一下, 等一下, 等一下. 你是谁...
calling me up out of nowhere?
为什么打电话给我?
How'd you get this number?
你怎么知道这号码?
I gotyour number out ofthe phone book.
我从电话簿上找到的.
I been calling Elkins all day.
我一直在找厄尔京.
Got no reason to lie toyou, ma'am.
我没有理由骗你, 太太.
Well, honey, Edward never mentioned no...
哦, 亲爱的, 爱德华从没有提起...
What's your name again?
再说一下你的名字?
Antwone.
安东尼.
I don't think he knew my motherwas pregnant.
我想他不知道我妈妈怀孕的事.
She was away in prison.
她逃狱了.
You know how he died?
你知道他怎么死的?
Yes, ma'am.
是的,太太 .
He was murdered by one ofhis girlfriends.
他被他的一个女朋友谋杀.
My God.
上帝啊.
Wait.
等一下.
What madeyou decide to show up...
是什么促使你决定讲出真相...
20-some-odd years later in the middle ofthe night?
在20多年后的午夜?
Mmm, that's a long story.
恩，那是个很长的故事.
But I'm in the navy...
但我在海军服役...
and, uh, I'm stationed on the west coast.
而且，我现在在西海岸.
I gotta get back in a few days.
过几天我就要回去了 .
Well, I--I wantyou to come by my house beforeyou go.
恩, 我-我希望你在走之前来一趟我家.
Okay.
好的.
Okay, look. Y-Y-You have a pencil?
好. 你有笔吗?
Take down my address.
抄一下我的地址.
Yeah.
恩哼.
It's 1 089 Drexel.
Drexel1089.
1 089 Drexel.
1 089 Drexel.
You know where that is?
你知道地方吗?
Yes, ma'am.
对，太太.
All right, well, come by my house tomorrow, hear?
好了, 明天来我这里，听见了吗?
- Okay. Um, ma'am... - Yes?
好的. 恩, 太太... 什么?
You mind if I bring my girlfriend with me?
我能不能带女朋友一起来?
Yes, fine. I'm--I'm looking forward to meeting her.
没有问题. 我 -我希望能看见她.
I'm sure she's looking forward to meeting you, too.
我相信她也希望见到您。
You--listen. You know, if--
你-听着. 你知道, 如果--
If Edward was your father...
如果爱德华是你父亲...
then you talking toyour auntie, son.
那你现在是在和你阿姨说话, 孩子.
You are talking toyour Auntie Annette...
你在和安妮特阿姨说话...
your daddy's baby sister.
你爸爸的小妹妹.
Well, I'll seeyou tomorrow.
哦, 我希望明天看见你.
I'll seeyou tomorrow.
明天见.
Good night.
晚安.
Bye.
再见.
I found them.
我找到他们了.
Hmm?
什么?
I found my family.
我找到我的家人了.
You did?
你找到了?
Mm-hmm.
恩-哼.
Oh, baby.
哦, 亲爱的.
Mmm.
恩.
I don't know. What doyou think?
我不知道. 你怎么想?
Well, he does look like Eddie.
哦，他长得很像埃迪.
I do?
是吗?
Yeah, you look just like him.
是的, 你长得很像他.
Mm-hmm.
恩哼.
I brought my birth certificate.
我带来了我的出生证明.
Born in '76.
76年出生.
That's theyear Edward died.
就是爱德华死的那年.
Antwone: Yeah, he-- He died in June...
哦，他-他六月死的...
and I was born in August.
我8月出生的.
And your mother's name is...
你妈妈叫...
- Eva Mae Fisher.
伊娃 梅 菲舍尔.
Eva?
伊娃?
I know Eva. That's Jess's sister.
我认识伊娃. 是杰西的妹妹.
Who?
谁?
Jess.
杰西.
You mean Fish?
你指菲舍尔?
Yeah, Fish. Jess Fisher.
对, 菲舍尔. 杰西-菲舍尔.
The boy's name is Antwone Fisher.
这孩子叫安东尼-菲舍尔.
That's Jess Fisher's sister, Eva Mae.
是杰西-菲舍尔的 妹妹, 伊娃-梅.
You know, Mae-Mae.
你知道, 梅-梅.
She live over there on Hodge Street.
她住在Hodge街.
No, I don't remember no Mae-Mae.
不, 我不认识什么梅-梅.
Y-You know where she lives?
你知道她住哪里?
You don't know her, do you?
你不认识她，是吗?
No. I--I--
是的. 我-我--
No, no.
不, 不.
You want to meet her?
你想见她?
Uh...
恩...
yeah.
是的.
Yeah, yeah.
对, 对.
You sure?
你确定?
'Cause we can take care ofthis right here and now.
因为我们现在有这个权力.
Yeah, I'm sure.
是的, 我确定.
Let me get my hat.
我去拿我的帽子.
Want me to go with you?
要我和你们一起去?
No, why don'tyou just stay here with us, baby?
不, 你为什么不和我们一起待在这里呢, 孩子?
Okay, let's ride.
好的, 走吧.
Bye.
再见.
You're not gonna let nothing happen to me, areyou?
你不会让我有事发生, 对吗?
No, Antwone.
是的, 安东尼.
I won't let nothing happen toyou.
我不会让你有事的.
Woman, Grouchy: Who is it?
谁?
Eva, it's James. James Elkins.
伊娃, 詹姆士. 詹姆士 厄尔克.
Edward's brother.
爱德华的弟弟.
Did you hear me, Eva?
你听见了吗, 伊娃?
This is James.
我是詹姆士.
Whatyou want?
有事吗?
Can we come in?
我们可以进去吗?
Hey, Eva.
嘿, 伊娃.
Hey.
嘿.
It's all right, son. Come on.
没事,孩子。 进来吧.
Who's that, Eva?
那是谁, 伊娃?
That's Johnny.
他是强尼.
No.
不.
That's Antwone Quenton Fisher.
他是安东尼-昆顿-菲舍尔.
Who's Antwone Quenton Fisher, Eva?
安东尼-昆顿-菲舍尔是谁, 伊娃?
That's my first-born son.
是我的长子.
[Sobbing] Oh, God.
哦, 上帝啊.
Ohh!
哦!
There's nothing going on around here.
什么事都没有发生.
You wanna stay?
你想继续待着?
I'm gonna stay.
我再待会儿.
I'll be in the car.
我在车里等.
Ahem.
啊咳.
You want something to eat?
你想吃点什么?
No.
不用了.
Why'd you never come for me?
为什么你从来不来看我?
Didn'tyou wonder where I was...
难道你不想知道我在哪里...
orwhat I was doing...
或者我在做什么...
orwhat I'd become...
我变得怎么样了...
or even if I was still alive?
我还活着吗?
Didn'tyou?
你为何不?
I've taken care of myself.
我可以自己照顾自己.
I have.
我可以.
I've never been in trouble with the law.
我没有犯过法.
I've read hundreds ofbooks...
我读了上百册的书...
written poems...
写了诗...
painted pictures.
画画.
I've traveled the world.
我还周游世界.
I serve my country.
我为国家效力.
I speak 2 languages...
我会2种语言...
and I'm working on a third.
我用第三种语言工作.
I never fathered any children.
我没有养过孩子.
I've never done drugs...
我不嗑药...
or even smoked a cigarette.
不抽烟.
I used to dream aboutyou.
我总是梦见你.
My mother.
我的母亲.
You know, what you'd be like.
你知道, 你什么样子.
Howyou look.
你的样子.
Yourvoice and your smile.
你的声音 和你的微笑.
Even your scent.
甚至你的气味.
For all theseyears I wondered aboutyou.
这些年来我一直记挂着你.
I dreamed aboutyou. Didn'tyou miss me?
我梦见你. 你不想我吗?
On thewayto school each day...
每一天去学校的路上...
I imagined you were just around the next corner...
我想像着您就在下一个街角...
and when I'd get there, you'd be there.
我到的时候, 你已经在那里了.
And in my mind, you was always there.
在我脑海里, 你总在那里.
You just couldn't find me.
你只是没有看到我.
So I'd race to the next corner...
所以我跑到下一个街角...
and you'd be there.
你已经在那里.
I'd knowyou would.
我知道你会的.
Then you would buy me ice cream.
然后你给我买冰淇淋.
And then you would take me home.
然后你带我回家.
I'm a good person.
我是个好人.
I'm a good man.
一个好男人.
Hey, boy, howyou doin'? I'm your Uncle Horace.
嘿, 孩子, 你好吗? 我是你霍勒斯叔叔.
Get out ofthe way, Horace. Come on, baby. Here he is!
让开, 霍勒斯. 快点, 亲爱的. 他来了!
Oh, look atyou! Look atyou!
哦, 让我看看你! 看看你!
I'm your Aunt Eda, baby.
我是你的伊塔姨妈, 孩子.
Ooh, I'm your cousin Jeanette.
哦, 我是你的加内特堂兄.
Welcome home!
欢迎回家!
And I'm your Aunt Anna. Howyou doin', baby?
我是你的安娜姨妈. 你好吗, 孩子?
This is mywife, "T."
这是我的妻子, "T."
Howyou doin', good-lookin'?
你好, 帅哥?
I'm your cousin Eddie.
我是你埃迪堂兄.
My dad named me afteryour father.
我爸爸以你父亲的名字给我取名.
And this is my brother Ray.
这是我弟弟雷.
Whassup, dog? What's crackin', man?
怎么了, 伙计? 怎么了, 朋友?
Hey, I'm your cousin Jason, man. What's happenin'?
嘿, 我是你詹森堂兄, 伙计. 怎么回事?
All right, boys, open up.
好了, 孩子们, 开始.
- Aww.
噢.
Welcome.
欢迎回来.
All right.
谢谢.
Come on, let's eat!
来吧, 开动!
You want some pancakes? Ooh.
薄饼要吗? 哦.
Sure, sure.
当然, 当然.
Here we go.
给.
How about some sausages?
香肠呢?
I'm not a virgin anymore.
我不是圣徒.
I'm glad to hear that.
很高兴听到这些.
Howyou doin', son?
你好吗,孩子?
I'm great, sir.
我很好, 长官.
All right. Good. Good, good.
好极了.
Very good to seeyou.
非常高兴见到你.
So?
是吗?
I tookyour advice.
我接受了你的建议.
I found my family and I found my mother.
我找到了我的家人，找到了我的母亲.
Good.
太好了.
Yeah.
是的.
So?
是吗?
Well, in my heart I forgive her...
恩, 我已经在心里原谅她了...
but ifl never saw her again...
就算我没有再见到她...
I understand.
我理解.
It's funny to feel that way aboutyour mother...
那种方式见到你妈妈感觉很滑稽...
but I did it...
但我做了...
and I owe it toyou to tell you thatyou were right.
我有义务告诉你，你是对的.
You owe it to me?
你有义务?
Yes, sir.
是的, 长官.
I needed to find her.
我必须找到她.
Yeah. Well...
是的. 恩...
ifl was right, it was for all the wrong reasons.
如果我是对的, 对所有人来说那是错误的理由.
Sir?
什么意思?
This stays between you and me, okay?
这是我们之间的谈话, 好吗?
Yes, sir.
好的, 长官.
Mywife and I, we were gonna have a bunch ofkids...
我和我妻子, 我们想要一打孩子...
when we found out we couldn't have any.
但我们不能有孩子.
And it rocked her to the core.
这深深地打击了她.
I knew what to do for her, though.
尽管我知道该为她做什么.
She needed help, treatment.
她需要帮助, 需要治疗.
I made sure she had it.
我确定她需要.
The best psychiatrist, the one that trained me.
最好的心理医生, 曾经治疗过我.
But I--the well one, the strong one--
但我-是最好的, 最棒的--
At the same time I went about the business of shutting down.
同时我开始做消极的事.
Very subtle, very quiet. It was my little secret.
很平淡，很安静. 这是我的秘密.
Until one day, a young man came into my office and into my life...
直到有一天, 一个年轻人闯进我的办公室，闯进我的生活...
and he blew up that little secret, right in my face.
他当着我的面揭开了那个秘密.
And he put me to shame in a way I never thought possible.
他让我觉得羞耻，用我想不到的方式.
Because ofyou, Antwone, I'm a better doctor...
因为你, 安东尼, 我成了一个好医生...
and I'm learning to be a better husband.
学习成为一个好丈夫.
You don't owe me anything. I oweyou.
你没有欠我的. 是我欠你的.
You're the champ, son.
你是冠军, 孩子.
You've beaten everybody who was beating you.
你已经打败了所有想打败你的人.
I saluteyou.
我向你致敬.
You hungry, sailor?
你饿吗, 水手?
I could eat, sir.
我会吃的, 长官.
Let's go.
走吧.